<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>Milwaukee County Blog</title>
    <link href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com" />
    <updated>2023-06-05T15:41:20-05:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Colin White</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://MkeCountyBlog.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Proton 2023: The Just Out Of Reach Ideal Privacy Suite</title>
        <author>
            <name>Colin White</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/proton-2023-the-just-out-of-reach-ideal-privacy-suite.html"/>
        <id>https://MkeCountyBlog.com/proton-2023-the-just-out-of-reach-ideal-privacy-suite.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/54/proton-logos.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Services"/>
            <category term="Proton Mail"/>
            <category term="Proton Drive"/>
            <category term="Proton Calendar"/>
            <category term="Proton"/>
            <category term="Privacy"/>
            <category term="Patience"/>
            <category term="CardDAV"/>
            <category term="CalDAV"/>

        <updated>2023-06-05T15:41:20-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/54/proton-logos.jpg" alt="Application icons of Proton&#x27;s suite of applications: Mail, Calendar, Drive, and VPN." />
                    Proton products has made great strides during last couple of years. At this point the email service along with Proton&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/54/proton-logos.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Application icons of Proton&#x27;s suite of applications: Mail, Calendar, Drive, and VPN." /></p>
                <p>Proton products has made great strides during last couple of years. At this point the email service along with Proton Bridge is exceptionally stable while providing a smoother experience than their non-trillion dollar competitors. As I see it, the natural next step for Proton Bridge should be the incorporation of the CalDAV and CardDAV protocols to enable contact and calendar syncing on PCs. That would transform their contact and calendar services from a proof of concept into something people can replace other products with (bonus points if added as a provider in Gnome Online Accounts.)</p>
<p>Email, calendar, and contacts functionality are interconnected so bundling them into one application makes a lot of sense. On mobile devices I'd like contacts to be a standalone app; for example, on an iPhone I would tap on Proton Contacts instead of the builtin Contacts app to call people and setup new contacts. This is already how Proton Calendar, Drive, and Email work.</p>
<p>Proton Drive is presently preparing the structure of their services for mass adoption so its usefulness remains a distant flicker. Sharing is functional and it sounds like the desktop client may be right around the corner. Much like contacts and calendars, everything but email feels perpetually unfinished with a solid, usable product constantly just out of reach. I hope that the sprinkling of improvements over the last year will grow into a cascade of highly usable cross platform products that allow users to consolidate everything into a wonderful Proton suite.</p>
<p>Some complain about how long Drive desktop client development is taking; it appears Proton is (wisely) trying to implement the polished functionality of something like Dropbox and Google Docs/Sheets so that everything just works upon broad release. As they target general users of Microsoft’s Office365 and Google Workspace, Proton understands any breakage or file loss will send users running for the hills loudly warning others to beware at all costs.</p>
<p>Owing to the added complexity developing encrypted alternatives entails, they will always remain one step behind their competitors in all but privacy and (idealy) security. I predict Proton Drive functionality will be close to as stable as Dropbox with considerably slower sync speeds. Still, I’m glad there is a company dedicated to providing an encryption-wrapped alternatives for those of us that place higher value on those principals.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Dishing Out Controversy: Milwaukee&#x27;s New Food Truck Laws Stir Up Questions of Fairness</title>
        <author>
            <name>Colin White</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/dishing-out-controversy-milwaukees-new-food-truck-laws-stir-up-questions-of-fairness.html"/>
        <id>https://MkeCountyBlog.com/dishing-out-controversy-milwaukees-new-food-truck-laws-stir-up-questions-of-fairness.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/53/tj-dragotta-wGm2-XxaDCY-unsplash.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="Tyler Cowen"/>
            <category term="Shenanigans"/>
            <category term="Overregulation"/>
            <category term="Milwaukee Common Council"/>
            <category term="Food Trucks"/>

        <updated>2023-05-24T21:55:37-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/53/tj-dragotta-wGm2-XxaDCY-unsplash.png" alt="Food truck operator pointing up to the taco sign on his truck." />
                    “City leaders have proposed legislation around food trucks that would regulate where, when and how they can operate in certain&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/53/tj-dragotta-wGm2-XxaDCY-unsplash.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Food truck operator pointing up to the taco sign on his truck." /></p>
                <blockquote>
<p>“City leaders have proposed legislation around food trucks that would regulate where, when and how they can operate in certain areas of the city in an attempt to cut back on all-out bans while reining in bad actors.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Lets see what <a href="https://www.jsonline.com/story/entertainment/dining/2023/05/15/milwaukee-food-trucks-proposed-ordinance-laws-rules/70209252007/" title="Milwaukee food trucks would face stricter regulation under proposed ordinance" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the Milwaukee Journal Sentinel article</a> tells us about it. There are three questions to ask when considering new regulation,</p>
<ol>
<li>What problem is being solved?</li>
<li>How common is the problem?</li>
<li>Is it a big enough problem to justify restricting the liberty of others?</li>
</ol>
<p>Based upon this article the problem appears to be some excess garbage, bright lights, and some noise; these are pretty minor issues and we aren't told how widespread they are.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Food trucks do need licenses from the city and are subject to inspection by the food department. They also are currently subject to other restrictions such as having to restrict noise and be in compliance with the Police Department.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>So the specified problems are already covered under existing regulations...</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“A Type 1 zone will not have limits on the number of food trucks that can be in a space, but a food truck cannot be parked in the zone for more than six hours in a 12-hour period. Food trucks in Type 1 also cannot serve food after 1 a.m.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>First, these rules will only apply at designated areas but I imagine the number of covered areas will expand considerably over time. Why stop people from selling food after 1am? The bars are still open and the trucks are going to park where the best chance to sell food is; probably by the bars which also produce the stated problems. Many fast food restaurants stay open 24/7; what’s different about food trucks that requires these limits?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“A Type 2 zone will only allow a certain number of food trucks on a block, and each food truck will have a permanent parking space. Food trucks will apply for those spaces, with their applications reviewed by the licensing committee. In Type 2 zones, food trucks may not operate after 3 a.m. Monday through Friday, and not after 3:30 a.m. on Saturdays and Sundays.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Why not enforce existing parking restrictions instead; if they park in a 2 hour zone then they can feed the meter and park for 2 hours. If the truck covers more than one space they can feed multiple meters. Once again there are unnecessary time restrictions; they will setup shop where customers are, not on quiet streets where everyone is asleep.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“In Type 2 zones, parking spaces will be assigned based primarily on seniority, or the number of years an applicant reports operating there. Applicants will receive additional seniority points if their vehicle is not larger than 12 feet in length, 11 feet in height and 7 feet in width. If food trucks are tied for a spot, the city will consider other factors such as which one has been licensed with the city the longest, which has a higher grade from the food department, and which has fewer disciplinary actions from the city.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>So there will be a limited amount of spaces and the incumbents will get priority therefore making it more difficult for startup food trucks to grow. Why not auction off the spaces instead? Those that value the space most will pay more to obtain it. Eliminates potential shenanigans related to the city picking winners (and losers.)</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“In all zones, food trucks under the new legislation will not be able to operate within 50 feet of a restaurant that doesn't have a drive-through, with the option for the Common Council to waive this restriction.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>And here we have the buried lede or the actual spark for these new rules. Restaurants (understandably) don’t like competition sitting outside their front door. If I’m a restaurant owner, I have to to pay rent (or property taxes) and employees; food trucks are often owner operated and get to drive around to high traffic areas and lour customers with (mostly) lower prices.</p>
<p>I wonder how many high traffic streets have enough restaurants in close proximity that the 50ft restriction essentially act as a ban? This reminds me of a Tyler Cowon article from today titled, “Attack monopoly power with deregulation.”</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Based on a study of regulatory comments, Singla also found that <strong>large firms oppose regulation in general, but push for regulation when such rules and laws damage the interests of smaller firms</strong>. Singla also finds that regulatory costs have increased significantly since the late 1990s.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In this case it isn’t large food truck companies crowding out smaller food trucks but restaurant owners pushing away potential rivals. I imagine the restaurant owners would argue that the trucks block their signage, take up street parking, or crowd the sidewalk near their place of business however all of these are public amenities and therefore should be open to food trucks as well in my opinion.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>MCB General Update: May 2023</title>
        <author>
            <name>Colin White</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/mcb-general-update-may-2023.html"/>
        <id>https://MkeCountyBlog.com/mcb-general-update-may-2023.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/52/townOfMilwaukeeTownHall.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="Town of Milwaukee"/>
            <category term="MCB Update"/>

        <updated>2023-05-07T13:51:13-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/52/townOfMilwaukeeTownHall.png" alt="Front porch of original Town of Milwaukee Town Hall with a wood bench and old light fixture against clapboard wall." />
                    When I first started this blog, the plan was to design the website around the MCTS bus system. The initial&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/52/townOfMilwaukeeTownHall.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Front porch of original Town of Milwaukee Town Hall with a wood bench and old light fixture against clapboard wall." /></p>
                <p>When I first started this blog, the plan was to design the website around the MCTS bus system. The initial website url was mkeCountyB.us and I used an edited photo of a county bus for the large photo when people visit the website. The blue, green, yellow color scheme feels inviting to me. An early post (the reason for starting the blog) proposed <a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/grid-milwaukees-bus-routes.html" title="Grid Milwaukee's Bus Routes" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">griding the Milwaukee County bus routes</a> to make riding the bus more attractive to a broader swath of county residents therefore increasing ridership and MCTS finances.</p>
<p>At the time I had further ambitions such as <em>Milwaukee County Podcast</em> and perhaps a coffee shop in Bayside named <em>Milwaukee County Cafe</em>; over time my feelings towards <em>Milwaukee County Blog</em> tilted towards it being too generic so that may change as well later on. In the meantime, there's a new image for the front page of the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Town_of_Milwaukee_Town_Hall" title="Town of Milwaukee Town Hall" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Town of Milwaukee Town Hall</a> located next to a beautiful stretch of Glendale next door to their town hall and across the street from Parkway Elementary School.</p>
<p>To me the building signifies the close connection the city and county have long shared and better represents my own connection to the area. The MCB color scheme will remain but the silly bus centered design is no more after three years of serving its purpose of getting me up and writing.</p>
<p> </p>
<div class="gallery-wrapper"><div class="gallery"  data-is-empty="false" data-translation="Add images" data-columns="2">
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/52/gallery/IMG_8312.jpg" data-size="4032x3024"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/52/gallery/IMG_8312-thumbnail.webp" alt="Town hall closer up flanked by two budding trees." width="720" height="540"></a></figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/52/gallery/IMG_8316.jpg" data-size="4032x3024"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/52/gallery/IMG_8316-thumbnail.webp" alt="Town hall from a distance with a large tree in front of it." width="720" height="540"></a></figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/52/gallery/IMG_8323.jpg" data-size="4032x3024"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/52/gallery/IMG_8323-thumbnail.webp" alt="Town hall front porch with an old light fixture and a bench." width="720" height="540"></a>
<figcaption>A welcoming porch.</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/52/gallery/IMG_8318.jpg" data-size="3024x4032"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/52/gallery/IMG_8318-thumbnail.webp" alt="Town hall historic marker." width="720" height="960"></a>
<figcaption>Oldest government building in the county.</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/52/gallery/siteLogoItalics.png" data-size="2205x772"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/52/gallery/siteLogoItalics-thumbnail.webp" alt="Milwaukee County bus with Milwaukee County Blog written along the top." width="720" height="252"></a>
<figcaption>The original Hero image; may it forever be saved on this page.</figcaption>
</figure>
</div></div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Coach Budenholzer Should Not Have Been Fired</title>
        <author>
            <name>Colin White</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/coach-budenholzer-should-not-have-been-fired.html"/>
        <id>https://MkeCountyBlog.com/coach-budenholzer-should-not-have-been-fired.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/50/solemnBuck.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="Unwise Firings"/>
            <category term="Mike Budenholzer"/>
            <category term="Bucks"/>

        <updated>2023-05-05T09:31:34-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/50/solemnBuck.png" alt="Dark background with solemn buck at the center." />
                    From a Casino.org post. Budenholzer led the Bucks to a Central Division crown in five consecutive seasons. He posted a&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/50/solemnBuck.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Dark background with solemn buck at the center." /></p>
                <p>From a <a href="https://www.casino.org/news/milwaukee-bucks-fire-head-coach-mike-budenholzer-after-first-round-upset/" title="Milwaukee Bucks Fire Head Coach Mike Budenholzer After First-Round Upset" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Casino.org post</a>.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Budenholzer led the Bucks to a Central Division crown in five consecutive seasons. He posted a 271-120 record, and won over 69% of his regular-season games during his five-year stint in Milwaukee.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>A highly successful coach that guided the Bucks to their first championship in 50 years should be revered not canned. The Bucks are dumping a top 5 coach.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Wisconsin Farm Death Used In Availability Cascade Attempt</title>
        <author>
            <name>Colin White</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/wisconsin-farm-death-used-in-availability-cascade-attempt.html"/>
        <id>https://MkeCountyBlog.com/wisconsin-farm-death-used-in-availability-cascade-attempt.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/48/s-turby-ZQPv1rdHEzg-unsplash.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Reporters"/>
            <category term="ProPublica"/>
            <category term="Marc Andreessen"/>
            <category term="Immigration"/>
            <category term="Farms"/>
            <category term="Death"/>
            <category term="Dairy"/>
            <category term="Availability Cascade"/>

        <updated>2023-03-16T15:28:45-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/48/s-turby-ZQPv1rdHEzg-unsplash.jpg" alt="An old red barn along a dirt road." />
                    Here's a recent ProPublica article about a 8 year old boy that was killed during an accident on a Dane&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/48/s-turby-ZQPv1rdHEzg-unsplash.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="An old red barn along a dirt road." /></p>
                <p>Here's <a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/wisconsin-dairy-farm-death-officials-respond" title="Officials Move to Address Problems Facing Immigrant Workers on Wisconsin Dairy Farms" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a recent ProPublica article</a> about a 8 year old boy that was killed during an accident on a Dane County farm in 2019. The headline tells us that officials are moving to address problems facing immigrant workers on Wisconsin dairies. A new employee operating <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Skid-steer_loader" title="Wikipedia - Skid-steer loader" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a skid-steer</a> at night ran over the boy at the now closed farm.</p>
<p>The parents are suing the farm and its insurance company and the lawyers have started their twisting of information this way and that for an advantage. Anywhoo, this article nicely demonstrates an attempt by ProPublica to spark an availability cascade; an idea <a href="https://pmarca.substack.com/p/availability-cascades-run-the-world" title="On Availability Cascades" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Marc Andreessen discussed in February</a>. In this instance the authors take an uncommon event (had to go back to 2019 to find a death related to an immigrant dairy worker) and try to cause enough outrage that people share the article widely and lead the public to feel that,</p>
<blockquote>
<p>What happened to Jefferson and his father is a story of an accumulation of failures: a broken immigration system that makes it difficult for people to come here even as entire industries depend on their labor, small farms that largely go unexamined by safety inspectors, and a law enforcement system that’s ill equipped to serve people who don’t speak English.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>It's good to see a man's name cleared in the death of his son but the authors dug up a 4 year old tragedy in order to encourage immigration reform, OSHA oversight of already struggling small farms (farms with under 10 non-family employees,) and for rural police to use better translation services. Wisconsin <a href="https://www.nass.usda.gov/Statistics_by_State/Wisconsin/Publications/Dairy/" title="USDA's National Agricultural Statistics Service Wisconsin Field Office" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">dairy herds shrunk</a> from 10,541 in 2014 to 6,071 in March 2023. The article also doesn't present the cost of the translation services which may explain why rural police departments consider them a last resort. In general they point out what they see as issues without mentioning why those issues exist. </p>
<p>Later in the article the authors state explicitly what their reporting is seeking out.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>We plan to keep reporting on issues affecting immigrant dairy workers across the Midwest. Among those issues: traffic stops of undocumented immigrants who drive without a license; access to medical care or workers’ compensation after injuries on the job; and employer-provided housing.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I found some Wisconsin agricultural death statistics within these <a href="https://marshfieldresearch.org/Media/Default/NFMC/WI%20Farm%20Fatality%20Report/2017%20Farm%20Fatality%20Report%20Final.pdf" title="2017 Wisconsin Farm Related Fatalities" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">2017</a> and <a href="https://marshfieldresearch.org/Media/Default/NFMC/WI%20Farm%20Fatality%20Report/2018%20Farm%20Fatality%20Report.pdf" title="2018 Wisconsin Farm Related Fatalities" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">2018</a> Marshfield Research Reports; out of the <a href="https://datcp.wi.gov/Pages/Publications/WIAgStatistics.aspx" title="Wisconsin Agricultural Statistics" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">154,000 on-farm Wisconsin jobs</a>, 41 people died in 2017 and 34 died in 2018. Wisconsin is really bad at gathering and presenting useful data as demonstrated by the reports first paragraph which ends saying "due to time and resource limitations, this report had been discontinued from 2007-16." If I had to guess, these limitations returned after 2018 because I can't find more recent statistics. It's similar to the complaints surrounding <a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/the-role-of-bail-on-milwaukee-crime-increases.html" title="The Role Of Bail On Milwaukee Crime Increases">crime committed while people are on bail</a>. In that instance we lack statistics related to how many people on bail are committing crimes.</p>
<p>It's difficult to make reasonable judgements without pertinent information to guide us.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Out Of State Landowners Are Not Predatory</title>
        <author>
            <name>Colin White</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/out-of-state-landowners-are-not-predatory.html"/>
        <id>https://MkeCountyBlog.com/out-of-state-landowners-are-not-predatory.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/47/saketh-garuda-7DziDCBnhiE-unsplash.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Rental"/>
            <category term="Out-Of-State 😱"/>
            <category term="Neighborhoods"/>
            <category term="Landlords"/>
            <category term="Investors"/>
            <category term="Homeowners"/>
            <category term="Census"/>

        <updated>2023-03-07T17:14:13-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/47/saketh-garuda-7DziDCBnhiE-unsplash.jpg" alt="Aerial photo of a Milwaukee neighborhood in summer." />
                    Milwaukee government and the local press continue to bang the drum of home ownership. Their idea is reasonable enough: 1)&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/47/saketh-garuda-7DziDCBnhiE-unsplash.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Aerial photo of a Milwaukee neighborhood in summer." /></p>
                <p>Milwaukee government and the local press continue to bang the drum of home ownership. Their idea is reasonable enough: 1) as homeowners normally take pride in their house and make efforts to keep it in good condition 2) and don't move as often, 3) more homeowners in troubled neighborhoods raises the potential to develop relationships and trust among neighbors 4) thus alleviating some of our local social issues such as violence, reckless driving, etc.</p>
<p>Recent news stories based upon statistics from <a href="https://milwaukeehousingstats.info/" title="Milwaukee Housing Trends since 2018" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">John D. Johnson's living report</a> proclaim out-of-town private equity groups predatory for buying up affordable housing stock that local homeowners would otherwise purchase. <a href="https://www.zillow.com/homes/for_sale/?searchQueryState=%7B%22pagination%22%3A%7B%7D%2C%22mapBounds%22%3A%7B%22west%22%3A-88.0101026584772%2C%22east%22%3A-87.91912212869204%2C%22south%22%3A43.06818838639472%2C%22north%22%3A43.13323942175906%7D%2C%22isMapVisible%22%3Atrue%2C%22filterState%22%3A%7B%22sort%22%3A%7B%22value%22%3A%22globalrelevanceex%22%7D%2C%22ah%22%3A%7B%22value%22%3Atrue%7D%7D%2C%22isListVisible%22%3Atrue%2C%22mapZoom%22%3A13%7D" title="Zillow Real Estate &amp; Homes For Sale" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">A quick search of these neighborhoods on Zillow</a> lists numerous houses for sale ranging from $16 thousand to $200 thousand.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Predatory</strong></p>
from The American Heritage® Dictionary of the English Language, 5th Edition.<br>
<ul>
<li><em>adjective</em> Living or characterized by preying on other animals.</li>
<li><em>adjective</em> Living or characterized by plundering, pillaging, or marauding.</li>
<li><em>adjective</em> Living or characterized by the exploitation of others for personal gain.</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>
<p>Helping people that have the means and desire to own a house is admirable but villainizing landlords is unnecessary. Milwaukee has ample low priced housing in the reported areas because there is continually above average crime rates, low performing schools, and less amenities (essentially the results of concentrated poverty) which lowers demand to live there despite the close distance to downtown. The housing stock around the city tends to be older and more expensive to maintain; when a house built in 1912 has a problem it will cost substantially more to fix compared with a similar problem in something built in 1990 for example.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Dorothy York, the vice president of real estate for Acts Housing, a nonprofit that helps low-income families become homeowners, said it’s important not to paint all investors in the same light.<br><br>“Predatory investors are often out-of-state companies that come into usually low-income neighborhoods, take advantage of the community and have destabilizing effects on the neighborhood,” she said. “But we’ve had investors in Milwaukee for years that have been providing safe affordable rental units to people and those are essential.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Johnson's original report is presented plainly (a great thing!) and does not make use of the word predatory. The <a href="https://urbanmilwaukee.com/2023/02/05/predatory-landlords-buying-up-city-properties/" title="Predatory Landlords Buying Up Milwaukee Properties" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Urban Milwaukee article</a> extracted the term from York's quote. Neither York nor the article describe how investors are "taking advantage of the community" or creating "destabilizing effects on the neighborhood." Is there evidence these neighborhoods have deteriorated more in the last 20 years then comparable districts nearby? How many low income families are trying to buy a home and failing because of the private equity groups? We hear a lot from local investors and non-profits that compete directly with the "predators" for houses but nothing from people that rent in these neighborhoods or the individuals looking to purchase a home there.</p>
<p>If a person/family has a stable income and some savings to tide them over when unexpected problems arise, owning a house can be wonderful. 24% of Milwaukee residents are in poverty <a href="https://www.census.gov/quickfacts/fact/table/milwaukeecitywisconsin/IPE120221#IPE120221" title="QuickFacts Milwaukee city, Wisconsin" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">according to the US Census Bureau</a>; based upon their specific circumstances many people determine that renting an apartment is their most prudent option. It could be that they would purchase a home but are unbanked or the desired house has one of the <a href="https://mymortgageinsider.com/five-property-appraisal-problems-risk-mortgage-approval-6364/" title="5 Appraisal Problems That Can Affect Your Mortgage Approval" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">problems common with old houses in Milwaukee</a> that lead to a denied mortgage. See below how poverty and renting line up in these districts and for an interactive map <a href="http://www.city-data.com/poverty/poverty-Milwaukee-Wisconsin.html#mapOSM?mapOSM[zl]=11&amp;mapOSM[c1]=43.05779457092285&amp;mapOSM[c2]=-87.96737289428711&amp;mapOSM[s]=poverty3&amp;mapOSM[fs]=false" title="Milwaukee, Wisconsin (WI) Poverty Rate Data" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">see City-Data.com</a>..</p>
<div class="gallery-wrapper"><div class="gallery"  data-is-empty="false" data-translation="Add images" data-columns="5">
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/47/gallery/0aldermanicDistricts.png" data-size="1344x2688"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/47/gallery/0aldermanicDistricts-thumbnail.webp" alt="2022 Aldermanic Districts" width="720" height="1440"></a>
<figcaption>2022 Aldermanic Districts (John Johnson - Milwaukee Housing Trends since 2018)</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/47/gallery/1totalHousesOwned.png" data-size="1344x1536"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/47/gallery/1totalHousesOwned-thumbnail.webp" alt="Total houses owned by an out-of-state landlord, September 2022" width="720" height="823"></a>
<figcaption>Total houses owned by an out-of-state landlord, September 2022 (John Johnson - Milwaukee Housing Trends since 2018)</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/47/gallery/2changeInOwnership.png" data-size="1344x1536"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/47/gallery/2changeInOwnership-thumbnail.webp" alt="Change in out-of-state ownership, 2018 - September 2022" width="720" height="823"></a>
<figcaption>Change in out-of-state ownership, 2018 - September 2022 (John Johnson - Milwaukee Housing Trends since 2018)</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/47/gallery/incomeBelowPovertyLevel.png" data-size="1026x873"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/47/gallery/incomeBelowPovertyLevel-thumbnail.webp" alt="Residents with income below the poverty level" width="720" height="613"></a>
<figcaption>Residents with income below the poverty level. Darker is higher percentage. (City-Data.com)</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/47/gallery/percentRenting.png" data-size="1026x873"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/47/gallery/percentRenting-thumbnail.webp" alt="Renting rate among poor residents." width="720" height="613"></a>
<figcaption>Renting rate among poor residents. Darker is higher percentage. (City-Data.com)</figcaption>
</figure>
</div></div>
<p>I imagine a family on a tight budget might prefer the more predictable expense of rent + utilities compared with the surprises that popup owning a house. If a rental property has a problem the landlord is <a href="https://www.tenantresourcecenter.org/repairs_in_wisconsin" title="Repairs in Wisconsin" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">generally responsible for fixing it</a>. If you are a homeowner, the asbestos/black mold/leaky roof/broken water heater/rodent problems are all paid for by you. If repairs are put off too long the cost to fix will grow and your house will degrade along with it's value and your quality of life. With rentals most of these costs will still be passed onto the renter through higher rent but that would be delayed until their lease expires at which point they have options.</p>
<p>I remain unconvinced that landlords (out-of-state or otherwise) are much of a problem (at least no more so than at any other point in time.) I think most of the problems effecting renters are due to extremely old, inefficient houses that aren't adequately maintained or perhaps some local management companies that are underperforming their responsibilities. The difference between a local owner versus out-of-state is minimal in this context as either way a local management company is the one servicing the properties.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>A Quick 1911 Bank Demolition Will Make Way For New Arts Center</title>
        <author>
            <name>Colin White</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/a-quick-1911-bank-demolition-to-make-way-for-new-arts-center.html"/>
        <id>https://MkeCountyBlog.com/a-quick-1911-bank-demolition-to-make-way-for-new-arts-center.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/46/firstWisconsin-2400x1592-upscaled.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="Old Buildings"/>
            <category term="Kirchhoff &amp; Rose"/>
            <category term="Historic Designation"/>
            <category term="Development"/>
            <category term="Construction"/>

        <updated>2023-01-24T17:34:00-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/46/firstWisconsin-2400x1592-upscaled.png" alt="Combined picture showing the main facade early in the 20th century next to today." />
                    BCA would demolish the two-story, 33,995-square-foot office building at 2312 N. Martin Luther King Jr. Dr. that was constructed in 1983. A&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/46/firstWisconsin-2400x1592-upscaled.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Combined picture showing the main facade early in the 20th century next to today." /></p>
                <blockquote>
<p>BCA would demolish the two-story, 33,995-square-foot office building at 2312 N. Martin Luther King Jr. Dr. that was constructed in 1983. A portion of the existing structure was built in 1911 as a Neoclassical-style bank branch. The DNR vacated the building in 2021 as part of a relocation to the Menomonee Valley.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="https://urbanmilwaukee.com/2023/01/24/eyes-on-milwaukee-design-team-chosen-for-bronzeville-arts-center/" title="Eyes on Milwaukee: Design Team Chosen For Bronzeville Arts Center Milwaukee" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The author</a> waits until the last paragraph to briefly mention the demolition of the 112 year old building designed by well respected Milwaukee architectural firm Kirchhoff &amp; Rose. Jeramey Jannene emphasizes that it's <em>constructed in 1983 </em>and only <em>a portion of the existing structure was built in 1911</em>. If the best part of a building was constructed in 1911 I'm inclined to say it was built in 1911 and substantially expanded in 1983.</p>
<p>The new building looks nice enough but it makes me wonder why this building appears to be getting a pass from the frantic historic preservation people. Had this been someplace on the East Side, Third Ward, or Downtown I imagine there would be a group of people complaining loudly to every politician and news organization they can find thus causing <a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/let-milwaukee-build.html" title="Let Milwaukee Build" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the city to delay everything for a year</a>. The project hasn't received approval yet so maybe I'm jumping the gun (I hope not.)</p>
<p>If only the design, review, demolish, build process could be this easy everywhere...</p>
<div class="gallery-wrapper"><div class="gallery"  data-is-empty="false" data-translation="Add images" data-columns="2">
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/46/gallery/firstWisconsin01-2400x1600-upscaled.png" data-size="1807x1187"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/46/gallery/firstWisconsin01-2400x1600-upscaled-thumbnail.webp" alt="Old neoclassical columned bank building." width="720" height="473"></a>
<figcaption>First Wisconsin Branch Bank as it looked in the old days.</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/46/gallery/firstWisconsin02-2400x1592-upscaled.png" data-size="2400x1592"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/46/gallery/firstWisconsin02-2400x1592-upscaled-thumbnail.webp" alt="DNR building as it looks today." width="720" height="478"></a>
<figcaption>A view of the former DNR building as it looks recently.</figcaption>
</figure>
</div></div>
<p>Above images from the Wisconsin Historical Society. For more information about the building <a href="https://www.wisconsinhistory.org/Records/Property/HI108845" title="2312 N 3RD ST - Architecture and History Inventory" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">visit this link</a>.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Marquette &amp; UWM Deserve Better Team Names</title>
        <author>
            <name>Colin White</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/marquette-and-uwm-deserve-better-team-names.html"/>
        <id>https://MkeCountyBlog.com/marquette-and-uwm-deserve-better-team-names.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/45/IMG_6799.jpeg" medium="image" />
            <category term="What&#x27;s In A Name"/>
            <category term="UWM"/>
            <category term="Sports"/>
            <category term="Martens"/>
            <category term="Marquette University"/>
            <category term="MATC"/>
            <category term="Industrial Terms"/>

        <updated>2023-01-24T08:15:53-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/45/IMG_6799.jpeg" alt="Fiserv Forum interior during Wisconsin Marquette game." />
                    Consider where your mind jumps when you hear mention of a Badger game compared with a Panther game. UW-Milwaukee's name&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/45/IMG_6799.jpeg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Fiserv Forum interior during Wisconsin Marquette game." /></p>
                <p>Consider where your mind jumps when you hear mention of a Badger game compared with a Panther game. UW-Milwaukee's name is indistinct while Marquette's never felt connected to the university. If you’re solely interested in a list of alternate names or cute animal pictures <a href="#NameLink" rel="nofollow">skip to the bottom</a> and enjoy; for a little history and reasoning continue on!</p>
<p>Panthers is a boring and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_college_team_nicknames_in_the_United_States" title="List of college team nicknames in the United States" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">widely used name of schools and teams across the United States</a> where the animal roams the zoos. <a href="https://guides.library.uwm.edu/c.php?g=56344" title="Mascots at UWM" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The UWM library</a> wrote that the university's naming developed as follows,</p>
<ul>
<li>1896: Wisconsin State Normal School Normals</li>
<li>1927: Milwaukee State Teacher's College Green Gulls</li>
<li>1956: University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee Cardinals (Wisconsin State College merged with the University of Wisconsin Extension)</li>
<li>1965: University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee Panthers</li>
</ul>
<p>As an outsider my feeling is UWM never fully habituated to either their school or team name. The <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/University_of_Wisconsin%E2%80%93Milwaukee#/media/File:University_of_Wisconsin%E2%80%93Milwaukee_seal.svg" title="Seal of University of Wisconsin–Milwaukee." target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">UWM seal</a> has three separate years on it which speaks towards the unsettled identity (if anyone has any idea why 1849 is on there please let me know!) As recently as 2006 the university name <a href="https://onmilwaukee.com/articles/wsu" title="Grassroots group lobbies for UWM name change" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">came up for reconsideration</a>.</p>
<p>People don't seem to mind the Panthers name but there isn’t much local connection with it either; we don’t see paraphernalia spread about the area as we do for the Bucks, Brewers or the Badgers in Madison. The Panthers are considerably less visible throughout Wisconsin. Even around Milwaukee few flags are flown, few sweatshirts are worn, and Pounce the Panther isn’t widely sought after for special occasions like Bucky.</p>
<p>Some of this certainly comes from an inconsistent program that has long gaps between  winning basketball seasons. A competitive team helps alumni and locals stay connected to a university from youth through adulthood. When the team is lousy for a decade or more at a time it's difficult to maintain a following and create connection. For an example look no further then the popular statewide support Badger athletics enjoy, even from some people with an active dislike of the university. Once the bonds form many people will continue to come even during dry spells.</p>
<p>Golden Eagles is a solid name but it was sutured on after the whole Marquette Warriors kerfuffle (let’s agree to forget the Marquette Gold hour.) Maybe the answer for them is to drop the nickname altogether and just go with Marquette; this is how they are mostly referenced anyways. Golden eagles are <a href="https://birdwatchinghq.com/eagles-in-wisconsin/" title="THE 2 TYPES OF EAGLES FOUND IN WISCONSIN! (ID GUIDE)" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">not very common in Wisconsin</a>; they come for food but nest elsewhere. On the other hand the name lines up well with the student population as <a href="https://www.marquette.edu/institutional-research-analysis/interactive-reports/freshman-dash.php" title="FIRST-YEAR STUDENT PROFILE INTERACTIVE REPORT">the majority come from Illinois</a>.</p>
<h4>Smaller school names.</h4>
<ul>
<li>Cardinal Stritch Wolves is solid.</li>
<li>Concordia Falcons is okay but frequently used.</li>
<li>MATC Stormers is excellent!</li>
<li>MSOE Raiders doesn't make a lot of sense here but is alright.</li>
<li>Wisconsin Lutheran Warriors uses one of the most common names.</li>
</ul>
<p>I think of a proper name as the initial step towards what has existed in Madison for the better part of a century; a culture that continuously draws tens of thousands of people together to witness, support, and celebrate local students competing against others around the country. When done well the camaraderie spreads wherever alumni or fans happen to live and is consistent through thick and thin. UW has this; Marquette has some of this; UWM has very little of this.</p>
<p>Below are ideas for any local institution pondering a name change in no particular order.</p>
<h4 id="NameLink">Alternate Names</h4>
<ul>
<li>Black Bears/<a href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/1264753" title="Alleged American Indian " baribal="" american="" black="" bear="" :="" a="" query="" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Baribals</a> – might be a tough sell in Packer country.</li>
<li>Cougars/Lions/Pumas – Milwaukee lion anyone?</li>
<li><a href="https://dnr.wi.gov/topic/endangeredresources/animals.asp?mode=detail&amp;speccode=amajf01040" title="American Marten (Martes americana)" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Martens</a> – <a href="https://i.pinimg.com/736x/13/b1/65/13b1659aaa22c9c641d83d0061233a42.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">remarkably cute animal</a> native to Wisconsin (albeit endangered.)</li>
<li>Forgers – <a href="https://www.pradeepmetals.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/closed-die-forging.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">shaping metal</a>, not faking checks 😉.</li>
<li>Trappers – works both historically and with basketball although it may be unpopular nowadays.</li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sprocket" title="Sprocket" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sprockets</a> – Industrial terms are underutilized in sports.</li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pinion" title="Pinion" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Pinions</a> – See above.</li>
<li>Casters – metal into a mold.</li>
<li>(Red) Foxes</li>
<li>Coyotes</li>
<li>Gray Wolves – may lead to the gray versus grey argument.</li>
<li>(River) Otters</li>
<li>Moles</li>
<li>Machine</li>
<li>Ticks</li>
<li>Bobcats – meh.</li>
</ul>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Jingoism</title>
        <author>
            <name>Colin White</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/jingoism.html"/>
        <id>https://MkeCountyBlog.com/jingoism.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/44/datingjungle-RloS06Kcz4-unsplash.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="WWI"/>
            <category term="Jingoism"/>
            <category term="Definitions"/>
            <category term="Areopagus"/>

        <updated>2022-12-28T14:53:04-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/44/datingjungle-RloS06Kcz4-unsplash.jpg" alt="Stellar ruins of Attica, Athens, Greece." />
                    By way of The Cultural Tutor's Areopagus newsletter. From a post contemplating World War I comes a definition of jingoism;&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/44/datingjungle-RloS06Kcz4-unsplash.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Stellar ruins of Attica, Athens, Greece." /></p>
                <p>By way of <a href="https://areopagus.culturaltutor.com/" title="Join the Areopagus" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Cultural Tutor's Areopagus newsletter</a>. From <a href="https://areopagus.culturaltutor.com/posts/areopagus-volume-xxiii" title="Areopagus Volume XXIII" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a post contemplating World War I</a> comes a definition of jingoism; my emphasis added in bold.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>A word is devalued when its definition becomes overextended. Jingoism doesn't simply refer to any sort of militaristic nationalism. Rather, its central quality is that profound excitement which Zweig described so eloquently, which Plutarch evoked on the streets of Athens, of <strong>youthful passion exploited by ignorance and patriotism fanned by the flames of ambition</strong>.</p>
</blockquote>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>MCB Technical Update: November 2022</title>
        <author>
            <name>Colin White</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/mcb-technical-update-november-2022.html"/>
        <id>https://MkeCountyBlog.com/mcb-technical-update-november-2022.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/43/claudia-wolff-owBcefxgrIE-unsplash.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Zola"/>
            <category term="Static Site Generators"/>
            <category term="Publii"/>
            <category term="MCB Update"/>
            <category term="Dragons"/>
            <category term="CSS"/>

        <updated>2023-05-07T13:37:46-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/43/claudia-wolff-owBcefxgrIE-unsplash.jpg" alt="Woman sobbing beside a bed." />
                    Visually the blog hasn't changed much since a substantial overhaul in July but several weeks ago I started playing around&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/43/claudia-wolff-owBcefxgrIE-unsplash.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Woman sobbing beside a bed." /></p>
                <p>Visually the blog hasn't changed much since a substantial overhaul in July but several weeks ago I started playing around with some other static site generators after I noticed the footer had broken sometime in the last month. Publii has been an outstanding tool for building the blog from scratch but I grew frustrated when I (mistakenly 😅) thought a theme update broke my custom CSS. I was unable to fix the problem within a reasonable time frame so I decided to look for greener pastures elsewhere.<br><br>I read about Hugo but several reviews pointed me towards something simpler named Zola (I like simple.) I spent some time reading and setting it up before deciding Publii provides everything I want in a considerably more convenient package. With Zola tagging, date beautification, image processing, site design, and other stuff would have to be researched, built, and tested before coming to parity with the existing website so I decided to just give up, dig in, and figure out what was causing my Publii woes.<br><br>It turned out to be my own lousy CSS tweaks that busted my footer and two hours later my main.css file was synced up with Publii's Simple Theme and Milwaukee County Blog is polished and humming along like the good old days of months past.<br><br>There are two lingering issues yet to find a resolution; if you have any ideas please get in touch below! The first is a spacing issue with a podcast iframe. There's too much whitespace below the iframe and my duct-tape fix broke my footer. The second issue is dragons within the built-in gallery. When a user hovers their pointer over an image, the caption displays over it but if there is a long caption it overlaps other photos so that when an user clicks a different image, the incorrect image expands instead. I'd like to simply disable the caption so that it only displays after someone clicks an image.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>CWT Quotations - Blattman and Gross</title>
        <author>
            <name>Colin White</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/cwt-quotations-blattman-and-gross.html"/>
        <id>https://MkeCountyBlog.com/cwt-quotations-blattman-and-gross.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/38/juri-gianfrancesco-rTFS5bQrXZk-unsplash_trimmed-2.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="University of Chicago"/>
            <category term="Tyler Cowen"/>
            <category term="Diet Coke"/>
            <category term="Daniel Gross"/>
            <category term="Chris Blattman"/>

        <updated>2022-09-29T10:43:16-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/38/juri-gianfrancesco-rTFS5bQrXZk-unsplash_trimmed-2.jpg" alt="Two men talking outside of a bar/cafe." />
                    A couple quotations from some recent Conversations With Tyler. First up a conversation from May 4th, 2022 with University of&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/38/juri-gianfrancesco-rTFS5bQrXZk-unsplash_trimmed-2.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Two men talking outside of a bar/cafe." /></p>
                <p>A couple quotations from some recent Conversations With Tyler. First up a conversation from May 4th, 2022 with <a href="https://conversationswithtyler.com/episodes/chris-blattman-whywefight/" title="Chris Blattman on War and Centralized Power (Ep. 149)" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">University of Chicago professor Chris Blattman</a>. University of Chicago strikes me as the ideal university environment; compare their ratings with <a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/marquette-and-wisconsin-disappoint-in-college-free-speech-rankings.html" title="Marquette &amp; Wisconsin Disappoint In College Free Speech Rankings" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">some Wisconsin universities</a>.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>COWEN: </strong>Last question. You teach at the University of Chicago. It still seems, to me, the place has a special ethos, a mix of seriousness, people teaching things to themselves, showing up meaning business, free speech, some cluster of ideas. How has the University of Chicago maintained that? What’s the secret there?<br><br><strong>BLATTMAN:</strong> I selected this place six years ago. In large part, that was one of its chief attractions, and I’ve asked myself that question. There’s a cheap answer, which is cultural persistence, but then, the question is why?<br><br><strong>COWEN: </strong>So many university cultures have changed, right?<br><br><strong>BLATTMAN:</strong> Maybe I’m going to go back and contradict myself — the political speech point. I think the university built its social identity around being that, and the reason you can point out this thing is not . . . Even if you didn’t spend any time there, you would be able to say that is the identity of this university because that’s what they say they are, and they show up in the news because they’re the university that does that.<br><br>It shouldn’t be surprising that a university has done that. <strong>The question is, why haven’t more universities done that?</strong> I was faculty at Yale, and I was faculty at Columbia, and they were many great things, but <strong>they were not places that self-consciously define themselves as places to be about ideas and about ideas at all costs</strong>. So it’s only in retrospect that I wonder why not.</p>
</blockquote>
<figure class="post__podcast"><div class="post__iframe"><iframe loading="lazy" width="300" height="150" style="height: 170px; max-width: 600px; width: 100%; border: 0;" src="https://podverse.fm/embed/player?episodeId=0By4JzisP" title="Podverse Embed Player" class="pv-embed-player"></iframe></div></figure>
<p>Here's one from the May 18th episode <a href="https://conversationswithtyler.com/episodes/daniel-gross/" title="Daniel Gross and Tyler Talk Talent (Ep. 150)" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">with Daniel Gross</a>.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>COWEN: </strong>Say you gave the Diet Coke question to someone who came to you with a start-up. What would count as a bad answer, and why would it be bad?<br><br><strong>GROSS: </strong>I think in interviews, in general, a very simple thing to look for that I’m still . . . By the way, I should mention a preemptive huge asterisk that I’ll only say once on this podcast, which is, I may say different hypotheses that I have, but they are opinions of a student, not of a master. I’m still learning.<br><br>But all of that said, I think sometimes in interviews, and when you meet people in general, there’s just a sense of being asleep or awake. Asleep is someone who doesn’t really even have the idea to think about the world as just like, maybe Diet Coke is something really good. What actually drives that? Someone who’s awake has actually had that thought already.<br><br>For me, the rejection of the question would really be the only bad answer, and I think that’s true in a lot of interviews in general. Like this very conversation we’re having — you can tell if people are having fun with each other’s questions and whatnot, or whether it’s monotonous. And someone who locks up and freezes when you ask them if maybe Diet Coke is correlated to productivity — which is a bit of a silly question at the end of the day — just the fact that they’re not having fun with it, I think, is something to look for.</p>
</blockquote>
<figure class="post__podcast"><div class="post__iframe"><iframe loading="lazy" width="300" height="150" style="height: 170px; max-width: 600px; width: 100%; border: 0;" src="https://podverse.fm/embed/player?episodeId=hubrE4sU-" title="Podverse Embed Player" class="pv-embed-player"></iframe></div></figure>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Marquette &amp; Wisconsin Disappoint In College Free Speech Rankings</title>
        <author>
            <name>Colin White</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/marquette-and-wisconsin-disappoint-in-college-free-speech-rankings.html"/>
        <id>https://MkeCountyBlog.com/marquette-and-wisconsin-disappoint-in-college-free-speech-rankings.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/35/jonah-brown-qt9V4RRZvOg-unsplash-2.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="University of Wisconsin"/>
            <category term="Ratings"/>
            <category term="Marquette University"/>
            <category term="Free Speech"/>
            <category term="College Free Speech Rankings"/>

        <updated>2022-09-12T19:49:05-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/35/jonah-brown-qt9V4RRZvOg-unsplash-2.jpg" alt="Students sitting in green grass at Marquette University with college buildings in background." />
                    The University of Wisconsin and Marquette University ranked average and below average respectively in the FIRE and College Plus 2022-2023&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/35/jonah-brown-qt9V4RRZvOg-unsplash-2.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Students sitting in green grass at Marquette University with college buildings in background." /></p>
                <p>The University of Wisconsin and Marquette University ranked average and below average respectively in the FIRE and College Plus <a href="https://rankings.thefire.org/" title="College Pulse Fire 2022-2023 College Free Speech Rankings" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">2022-2023 College Free Speech Rankings</a>. Wisconsin <a href="https://rankings.thefire.org/rank/school/university-of-wisconsin-madison" title="University of Wisconsin" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ranked #98</a> out of 208 schools with low ratings in most categories. Marquette <a href="https://rankings.thefire.org/rank/school/marquette-university" title="Marquette University" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ranked #184</a> out of 208 and has especially low ratings for everything except disruptive conduct.</p>
<p>Every school on the list, including #1 University of Chicago, lists quotes from students that feel they must hide thoughts that oppose the popular opinion of either their professors or fellow students in order to pass a class or not be socially shunned. The ratings were calculated from student survey results so this essentially provides a sampling of student perceptions of their chosen schools' speech climate. Unease appears to be common across the board.</p>
<p>These students notice, or at least believe, that their university does not respond well to differing opinions so they submit to the status quo to avoid retribution on their way to a diploma. I wonder how many of these students have voiced a (perceived) unpopular opinion in class or elsewhere? One person mentions that they don't want to discuss abortion at Marquette because "most students on campus are anti-choice." This represents an old problem; societies do not tend to encourage or enjoy people that push against what's expected. Expectations differ from group to group but the general principal remains. Could it be fear of a harsh reproach stops people from even trying it out or have these students witnessed repercussions firsthand? Perhaps this is what makes recognizing the problem and moving away from it such a slog (which people will also avoid.)</p>
<p>Placidity is society's equilibrium; employees of a university need to be humble and constantly pushing to facilitate a healthy exchange of differing ideas in their classrooms in order to shift the default towards something substantial. If all are quiet and/or there is hardly any disagreement voiced then you have work to do. Much like within business or solid relationships dissent helps strengthen good ideas and expose bad ones. Universities will benefit after students graduate and discover the vital confidence and skills they gained that are necessary to communicate effectively as adults.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Turn Sport Commentators Off</title>
        <author>
            <name>Colin White</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/turn-sport-commentators-off.html"/>
        <id>https://MkeCountyBlog.com/turn-sport-commentators-off.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/36/ESPN_College_Football_set_at_the_2018_College_Football_Playoff_National_Championship_media_day-2.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Washington State University"/>
            <category term="Unnecessary Statistics"/>
            <category term="University of Wisconsin"/>
            <category term="Sports"/>
            <category term="Sound"/>
            <category term="Score Box/Ticker"/>
            <category term="Reporters"/>
            <category term="Finger In The Eye"/>
            <category term="Commentators"/>
            <category term="Badger Football"/>
            <category term="Advertisements"/>

        <updated>2022-09-10T23:08:26-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/36/ESPN_College_Football_set_at_the_2018_College_Football_Playoff_National_Championship_media_day-2.jpg" alt="ESPN College Football set at the 2018 College Football Playoff National Championship media day." />
                    Sports commentators exist to fill all potential time viewers could have to think for themselves; the incessant talking and their&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/36/ESPN_College_Football_set_at_the_2018_College_Football_Playoff_National_Championship_media_day-2.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="ESPN College Football set at the 2018 College Football Playoff National Championship media day." /></p>
                <p>Sports commentators exist to fill all potential time viewers could have to think for themselves; the incessant talking and their overconfidence is an endless, unpleasant, distraction from the competition. They tell you the what and why of everything and repeat it over and over and over some more. For many years I have hoped sports networks would create a separate audio channel with only crowd noise and game sounds since these actually enhance the experience. MLB.TV has this but local games are blacked out so it’s not particularly useful for those that like to watch live.</p>
<p>I long to watch a game without the hollow commentator banter that only occasionally breaks away to a contractually obligated coach/player interview where we are treated to someone practiced in the ways of generalities and platitudes. They understandably speak that way in order to avoid offering opponents (or the press) actionable information but it provides nothing of substance.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>Michele Tafoya:</strong> Obviously emotional. What's the immediate feeling you're having right now?</p>
<p><strong>Aaron Donald: </strong>I feel so happy. I wanted it so bad. I dreamed this man!</p>
<p>- <a href="https://youtu.be/cMOomd6xOJw?t=99" title="Super Bowl LVI - Final Play + Postgame Interviews" target="null">First interview question</a> post Super Bowl LVI victory.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Each game someone in a back room does their damnedest to hunt down a new record (most stubbed toes!) or unique stat that is remarkably obscure and unimportant; today I learned Alabama football has the longest streak (19) of seasons with a 2-0 start in college football history 🤯. This reminds me of the reporters that shine up a story by adding a person’s gender, race, region, or religion in front of their accomplishment: the first female Latin person from Kalamazoo to become a 6<sup>th</sup> Circuit judge since 2003! The game (or personal accomplishment) is no longer enough of a spectacle to these people; if the event itself doesn't intrigue the viewer does surplus fluff actually draw them in?</p>
<p>Today I watched the Badgers lose to Washington State 🫠; the commentators rehashed a storyline about WSU’s coach being from Wisconsin ten times thus providing a finger in my eye to accompany Wisconsin’s unfortunate mistakes. Someone new to the game likely appreciates analysis that provides information about what is happening but considering how far video streaming technology has come I believe it’s long past time to provide an option for other users that lets us turn the commentators off.</p>
<p>Let the advertisements be as loud as need be (that’s a different can of worms) but please allow for some peace during the game. When you combine uninteresting commentary, the <a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/bally-sports-please-shrink-the-score-box.html" title="Bally Sports, Please Shrink The Score Box" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">comically large bottom score bars</a>, and the homogenization of major sports leagues I find my interest towards watching athletics to be waning considerably as time moves on. Maybe it's time to just watch championships and the Olympics and use my new free time on more productive endeavors. These networks may be doing me a favor.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The Collected Stories of Lydia Davis - Problem</title>
        <author>
            <name>Colin White</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/the-collected-stories-of-lydia-davis-problem.html"/>
        <id>https://MkeCountyBlog.com/the-collected-stories-of-lydia-davis-problem.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/34/patrick-tomasso-Oaqk7qqNh_c-unsplashBooks.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Y Chromosome"/>
            <category term="Questions"/>
            <category term="Books"/>

        <updated>2022-08-23T20:54:57-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/34/patrick-tomasso-Oaqk7qqNh_c-unsplashBooks.jpg" alt="Open books pinned to a wall creating a collage." />
                    / = is in a relationship with $ = gets money from X ($Z)(female) / Y (male) W ($Y+$V)(female) +&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/34/patrick-tomasso-Oaqk7qqNh_c-unsplashBooks.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Open books pinned to a wall creating a collage." /></p>
                <p>/ = is in a relationship with<br>$ = gets money from</p>
<p><strong>X</strong> ($Z)(female) / <strong>Y</strong> (male)<br><strong>W</strong> ($Y+$V)(female) + child (V) / <strong>U</strong> (male, no support to W's child) - Lives in NY<br><strong>V</strong> (male) - Wants to move to Chicago but child lives in NY<br><strong>T</strong> ($U)(female) + child (U) - Lives in NY</p>
<ol>
<li>Who is Z and where is their money coming from?</li>
<li>I wonder if Y sharing a letter with the male chromosome is a coincidence?</li>
</ol>
<p>The use of letters in place of names made this very difficult for me to process exactly what is happening; everything became jumbled in my mind. Now that I think about it, it probably would have been the same with or without names.</p>
<p>If you have no idea what story this relates to, <a href="https://smile.amazon.com/Collected-Stories-Lydia-Davis-ebook/dp/B004774AS0/" title="The Collected Stories of Lydia Davis Kindle Edition" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">get the book</a>; the stories are wonderfully concise.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>A Fix For Demonstrated Absentee Voting Vulnerability</title>
        <author>
            <name>Colin White</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/a-fix-for-demonstrated-absentee-voting-vulnerability.html"/>
        <id>https://MkeCountyBlog.com/a-fix-for-demonstrated-absentee-voting-vulnerability.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/33/david-clode-3udd_NEmgDs-unsplash.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Wisconsin Elections Commission"/>
            <category term="Wisconsin"/>
            <category term="Vulnerability Reporting"/>
            <category term="Voter Registration"/>
            <category term="Verification"/>
            <category term="MyVote"/>
            <category term="Election"/>
            <category term="Crime"/>
            <category term="Can&#x27;t see the forest for the trees"/>
            <category term="Absentee Ballot"/>

        <updated>2022-08-07T14:14:18-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/33/david-clode-3udd_NEmgDs-unsplash.jpg" alt="The head of this crocodile in a pond just looks like a log or rock covered in duckweed until you spot the eye looking at you." />
                    From a Wisconsin Public Radio article last Thursday, In a series of interviews with media outlets including Wisconsin Public Radio,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/33/david-clode-3udd_NEmgDs-unsplash.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="The head of this crocodile in a pond just looks like a log or rock covered in duckweed until you spot the eye looking at you." /></p>
                <p>From a <a href="https://www.wpr.org/racine-county-man-admits-fraudulent-requests-absentee-ballots-effort-criticize-state-voting-system" title="Racine County man admits to fraudulent requests for absentee ballots in effort to criticize state voting system" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wisconsin Public Radio article</a> last Thursday,</p>
<blockquote>
<p>In a series of interviews with media outlets including Wisconsin Public Radio, Harry Wait of Dover said he used the state's <a href="https://myvote.wi.gov/en-us/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">online voter portal</a> to request absentee ballots for Assembly Speaker Robin Vos, a Republican from Rochester, and Racine Mayor Cory Mason, Democrat.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Wait said he requested that the ballots be sent to a different address, but he never received the ballots [He says that he later received 5.]  He said he sent an email early the next morning notifying Racine County Sheriff Christopher Schmaling and District Attorney Patricia Hanson among others that he had taken the step.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>They leave out key information; <a href="https://rumble.com/v1dwx33-in-wi.-you-can-order-an-absentee-ballot-for-friends-family-or-a-mule.html" title="In WI. You Can Order an Absentee Ballot for Friends Family or a Mule" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">in his video</a> Wait wrote "the new address was inserted and <strong>indefinitely confined was selected ...no ID or proof was required</strong>." That is the flaw Wait is trying to expose that allowed him to receive other peoples' ballot. Reporters are more focused on pending criminal charges which downplays the rather large vulnerability that has been exposed; the current system enabled someone to receive other peoples' ballot.</p>
<p>From <a href="https://www.wpr.org/wisconsin-elections-commission-will-assist-investigation-fraudulent-absentee-ballot-requests" title="Wisconsin Elections Commission will assist with investigation of fraudulent absentee ballot requests" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a different article Wednesday</a>,</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Wait said he was able to request ballots for Vos and Mason by using their addresses and birthdates. Wait also reportedly requested the ballots of about 10 other friends with permission. On Tuesday, Wait said he had received five ballots back, including [Racine Mayor] Mason's.</p>
</blockquote>
<h4>How The Vulnerability Works</h4>
<ol>
<li>Clancy is an already registered voter.</li>
<li>A fraud (Ralph) logs in to the MyVote website using Clancy's name and birthday (public information.)</li>
<li>Ralph then requests an absentee ballot for Clancy and asks that it be mailed to a new address. Ralph enters both Clancy's mailing address (public information) and the nefarious new address.</li>
<li>Ralph <a href="https://elections.wi.gov/wec-form/absentee-ballot-request-el-121-121h-121s" title="WEC Absentee Ballot Request (EL-121, 121h, 121S)" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">checks the box on MyVote website or paper form</a> proclaiming "I certify that I am indefinitely confined" so that he does not need to submit Clancy's state ID.</li>
<li>Ralph patiently waits for Clancy's ballot to arrive in the mail and then fills it out the ballot.</li>
<li>Ralph has his friend Sam sign it or maybe forges Sam's information before dropping it in a mailbox. A fraudulent vote is thus cast.</li>
</ol>
<p><a href="https://www.cbs58.com/news/wisconsin-elections-commission-most-common-mistakes-people-make-on-absentee-ballots" title="Wisconsin Elections Commission: Most common mistakes people make on absentee ballots" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">We don't use signature verification</a> so after receiving someone else's ballot there doesn't appear to be a useful way for local clerks to identify a fraudulent vote. Fraud prevention is done <em>before</em> sending the ballot. One way to catch it is if the same person requests a ballot twice. What happens if a fraudster receives and submits your ballot and then you, the actual voter, tries to vote through the mail or in person on election day? I'm guessing the computer system flags this somehow and an investigation happens?</p>
<blockquote>
<p>In a memo to clerks, the WEC [Wisconsin Elections Commission] recommended that they examine incoming absentee ballot requests with a separate mailing address to identify possible fraudulent activity. The memo instructed clerks to contact voters to confirm any ballot requests that present concerns.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><span style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">The WEC recommendation drives home this point; what does a concerning mailing address look like and how does WEC expect clerks to identify them? Maybe if 5 different ballots are going to the same address a red flag is raised but what if one person is requesting a ballet go to a different county? I imagine clerks are busy and have to process a high volume of different types of requests and dumping this additional responsibility on them seems like the WEC shirking their duties.</span></p>
<p>I have seen no evidence of this being widely exploited nor of other widespread voting fraud in Wisconsin but step #4 above shows clearly why so many Wisconsinites are concerned. The ease of this abuse calls for the verification process to be tweaked in order to maintain/restore skeptical voters' trust. Ignoring an exposed problem like this will create much larger issues down the road.</p>
<p>The problem seems similar to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coordinated_vulnerability_disclosure" title="Coordinated vulnerability disclosure" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">software vulnerability reporting</a>. Somebody discovers and responsibly reports a flaw so that it can be quickly addressed (hopefully) and all users become a little bit better protected going forward. In this case, Wait is attempting to publicly demonstrate a problem within our current absentee voting system and embarrass our representatives into fixing it.</p>
<p>What follows is one potential fix; If you have other ideas or ways to improve it comment below or on Reddit! Indefinitely confined people that are unable to leave their home need to have their address and identity verified without creating a large burden for them. For those with internet access, require them to upload their photo ID using the same process as <a href="https://elections.wi.gov/wec-form/voter-registration-application-el-131-131h-131s" title="WEC Voter Registration Application (EL-131, 131H, 131S)" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">voter registration</a>. If they do not have internet access, a local government employee can visit their home and scan the proof of residence document or ID thus resolving the problem.</p>
<p>This assumes that the majority of indefinitely confined people have either mobile or wired internet access or a friend or family member that could help out (I may be wrong.) In either case, after successfully processing a change of address the local clerk's office would then mail a confirmation letter to the voter's original address as one final attempt to catch discrepancies.</p>
<p>Our goal in the great State of Wisconsin should be to have as many eligible people as possible cast their vote while making it as difficult as practical to manipulate the election process. There is more to be done on both of these fronts but it will require better efforts from state government and the WEC.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>At Wednesday's commission meeting, Spindell suggested the agency should explore new means of verification when people request absentee ballots. That motion failed 3-3 along party lines.</p>
</blockquote>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Common Council Makes Things Worse, Again</title>
        <author>
            <name>Colin White</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/common-council-makes-things-worse-again.html"/>
        <id>https://MkeCountyBlog.com/common-council-makes-things-worse-again.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/32/nazrin-babashova-lhVRa24EOSA-unsplash.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Milwaukee Common Council"/>
            <category term="Maps"/>
            <category term="Licensing"/>
            <category term="Death"/>
            <category term="Crime"/>
            <category term="Burger King"/>

        <updated>2022-11-06T17:22:09-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/32/nazrin-babashova-lhVRa24EOSA-unsplash.jpg" alt="Burger King on a foggy night. " />
                    “We understand the circumstances,” said Velarde. He said the day before the homicide an employee was shot at by a&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/32/nazrin-babashova-lhVRa24EOSA-unsplash.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Burger King on a foggy night. " /></p>
                <blockquote>
<p>“We understand the circumstances,” said Velarde. He said the day before the homicide an employee was shot at by a customer. “<strong>It’s a problem and it is bigger than us [this Burger King].</strong>”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Spoken by Cave Enterprises CEO Adam Velarde owner of a Burger King that the Milwaukee Common Council <a href="https://urbanmilwaukee.com/2022/06/22/council-closes-burger-king-with-inside-job-theft-shooting/" title="City Closes Burger King With Inside-Job Shooting" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">recently voted to close</a> by denying renewal of their food dealer license. <a href="https://urbanmilwaukee.com/2021/03/13/city-hall-council-closes-genes-supper-club/" title="City Hall: Council Closes Gene’s Supper Club" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">This</a> <a href="https://www.tmj4.com/news/local-news/mr-js-lounge-closes-after-45-years-following-milwaukee-common-council-vote" title="Mr. J's Lounge closes after 45 years following Milwaukee Common Council vote" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">seems</a> <a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/speedway-punished-for-being-repeatedly-robbed.html" title="Speedway Punished For Being Repeatedly Robbed" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">like</a> a burgeoning trend in town. </p>
<p>The city is helpless as many of our fellow citizens regularly harm others or their property. The politicians appear to believe it's their responsibility; that they hold the levers that will eliminate violence; they <em>must do something</em>. So they shutdown local businesses after they become the victims of reckless violence. It's something they can<em> </em>do. They can close places people go to eat or drink; they can remove jobs from a neighborhood.</p>
<p>What metric do they use to make these decisions? Is their cost benefit analysis gut based or do they have some statistics that demonstrates forcing closed a business lowers an area's crime levels? Will this be applied evenly everywhere in town since this is not a targeted problem? Do Milwaukee residents feel politicians are responsible for Burger King shootings? If so, what's the relationship?</p>
<p>To me it seems obvious the local government cannot fix what ails Milwaukee. The problems and solutions lie within the bodies and perceptions of those that continue to carry out these terrible acts that drag us all down. In the meantime, expect more businesses to be closed in neighborhoods that badly need more of them. Look at the map below; the Burger King death of Niesha Harris-Brazell is circled in red; each black marker represents another murder within the surrounding area as of June 24, 2022. Oddly enough, murders continue to happen right near the businesses the Council closed in the past.</p>
<p>Does anyone honestly believe that Burger King is the problem?</p>
<div class="gallery-wrapper"><div class="gallery"  data-is-empty="false" data-translation="Add images" data-columns="1">
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/32/gallery/2022murders.png" data-size="3326x1609"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/32/gallery/2022murders-thumbnail.webp" alt="Map showing murders in neighborhoods surrounding Burger King." width="720" height="348"></a>
<figcaption>Altered screenshot from the <a href="https://projects.jsonline.com/apps/Milwaukee-Homicide-Database/" title="Journal Sentinel - Milwaukee Homicides" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Milwaukee Journal Sentinel's Homicide Database</a>.</figcaption>
</figure>
</div></div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>I-94 East-West Rebuild - 8 Lanes Please</title>
        <author>
            <name>Colin White</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/i-94-east-west-rebuild-8-lanes-please.html"/>
        <id>https://MkeCountyBlog.com/i-94-east-west-rebuild-8-lanes-please.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/31/I94ewRebuild-2.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="Wisconsin DOT"/>
            <category term="Traffic"/>
            <category term="Pollution"/>
            <category term="Highway"/>
            <category term="Death"/>
            <category term="Construction"/>

        <updated>2022-08-01T19:06:57-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/31/I94ewRebuild-2.png" alt="Map displaying proposed section of I-94 to be rebuilt" />
                    Below is a copy of feedback I emailed to the Wisconsin DOT after attending a June 15th public involvement meeting&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/31/I94ewRebuild-2.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Map displaying proposed section of I-94 to be rebuilt" /></p>
                <p>Below is a copy of feedback I emailed to the Wisconsin DOT after attending a June 15th public involvement meeting at Marquette High School. Before that are some thoughts that came up after the fact. I look forward to hearing your thoughts!</p>
<h4>Thoughts &amp; Questions</h4>
<ul>
<li>We hear a lot about <a href="https://wisconsindot.gov/Pages/about-wisdot/newsroom/statistics/monthfatal.aspx" title="Wisconsin DOT Fatalities by month" target="null">road deaths in Wisconsin</a> but they aren't broken down by county or by highway versus road fatalities. My feeling is there are significantly more road deaths on streets versus highways. <strong>Anyone know of more detailed available data?</strong> It seems like the state could maintain a live map or dashboard of this information <a href="https://city.milwaukee.gov/police/Information-Services/Crime-Maps-and-Statistics" title="MPD Crime Maps &amp; Statistics" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">similar to what MPD does</a>.</li>
<li>Lots of commuters to and from Milwaukee are aware of daily traffic jams heading east and west on I-94 and therefore use side streets to bypass the traffic.</li>
<li>If an expanded highway with steady traffic flow attracts a decent percentage of those commuters thus removing them from side streets, won't that reduce traffic around neighborhoods and increase road safety in Milwaukee? Less people anxious to get home trying to beat yellow lights, etc.
<ul>
<li><strong>What time(s) of day do most fatalities occur? </strong></li>
<li><strong>How about vehicle crashes? </strong></li>
<li><strong>How many of the deaths are people in cars, motorcycles, or bicycles?</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h4><strong>Email to the DOT</strong></h4>
<p><em>Edited to remove a duplicate word.</em></p>
<p>I would like to see the 8 lane option installed. West bound traffic has been notoriously congested for many years and I know several people that adjust their work schedules and/or driving routes to avoid the worst of it everyday; some have been involved in accidents on side streets on their way home. After viewing the presentation Wednesday at Marquette High School it appears that the project’s footprint remains largely the same both with 6 or 8 lanes but the 8 lanes option will allow for a more steady flow of traffic during peak traffic times each day. Therefore the amount of gasoline vehicles waste idling in traffic is reduced and truckers can get goods from A to B in a more timely fashion.</p>
<p>In regards to the Brewers Way Interchange it should prioritize moving people in and out of the stadium area as quickly, safely, and efficiently as possible both for Brewers fans and highway drivers that happen to be passing by. Currently there are long backups on game days, particularly when coming from the west. It sounds like the ground level North South option will slow down traffic and increase the amount of time it takes drivers to get to businesses in the area south of American Family Field; this seems like a negative to me although the cost savings are excellent. I would be interested to hear what business owners and commuters from that area think as locals may prefer the more inviting street level road compared to the more imposing highway.</p>
<p>I’m glad to see highway ramps universally placed on the right side of I-94 thus allowing the fast lane to maintain a steady, uninterrupted flow. In regards to concerns about the negative effects of pollution on nearby neighborhoods I imagine large amounts of slow moving cars would create larger concentrations of pollution in the area compared to faster moving traffic although this assumption may well be incorrect. Here is one study on the subject that appears to agree with my assumption, <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4243514/">https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4243514/</a>.</p>
<p>It is vital to the region that bottlenecks along that part of the highway are minimized to allow for the efficient movement of people and goods around our area. Places west of Milwaukee are growing rapidly and the Milwaukee to Madison route connects the state’s two largest metro areas.</p>
<p>Many thanks for your years of work regardless of the final decision; let’s get this built!</p>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center" ><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/31/I94ewRebuildTrafficOperations.png" alt="Traffic Operations by Alternatives" width="1600" height="1036" sizes="100vw" srcset="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/31/responsive/I94ewRebuildTrafficOperations-xs.webp 300w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/31/responsive/I94ewRebuildTrafficOperations-sm.webp 480w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/31/responsive/I94ewRebuildTrafficOperations-md.webp 768w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/31/responsive/I94ewRebuildTrafficOperations-lg.webp 1024w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/31/responsive/I94ewRebuildTrafficOperations-xl.webp 1360w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/31/responsive/I94ewRebuildTrafficOperations-2xl.webp 1600w">
<figcaption >Pardon the weird coloring. I snapped a picture of this board at the meeting. The 8 lane options seem to get rid of most of the congestion. © MCB - Colin White</figcaption>
</figure>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The St. Louis Idea – Build Momentum</title>
        <author>
            <name>Colin White</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/the-st-louis-idea-build-momentum.html"/>
        <id>https://MkeCountyBlog.com/the-st-louis-idea-build-momentum.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/30/StLouisbrittney-butler-uZnoD1xuL9A-unsplash.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Venture Capital"/>
            <category term="Tyler Cowen"/>
            <category term="St. Louis Idea"/>
            <category term="St. Louis"/>
            <category term="Sam Altman"/>
            <category term="Momentum"/>
            <category term="Midwest"/>

        <updated>2022-08-02T11:54:28-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/30/StLouisbrittney-butler-uZnoD1xuL9A-unsplash.jpg" alt="The Old St. Louis County Courthouse with the St. Louis Arch in the background." />
                    On an old episode of Conversations With Tyler from 2019, Tyler Cowen asked St. Louis native Sam Altman the following,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/30/StLouisbrittney-butler-uZnoD1xuL9A-unsplash.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="The Old St. Louis County Courthouse with the St. Louis Arch in the background." /></p>
                <p>On an <a href="https://conversationswithtyler.com/episodes/sam-altman/" title="Sam Altman on Loving Community, Hating Coworking, and the Hunt for Talent (Ep. 61 - Live in SF)" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">old episode of Conversations With Tyler</a> from 2019, Tyler Cowen asked St. Louis native <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sam_Altman" title="Sam Altman" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Sam Altman</a> the following,</p>
<blockquote>
<p>If you had, say, $200 million to distribute, you could do with it whatever you wanted to help St. Louis — just St. Louis, not the world — what would you do to help St. Louis?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>St. Louis, like most Midwestern cities, flourished until the 1960's at which point a steep economic decline ensued along with an exodus of people; they have been stagnant since. As these cities have been outdone by the Southeastern United States and coastal cities, they badly need to implement new ways of doing things that have the potential to spark a return to forward momentum. For all of the small improvements we have seen in Milwaukee and similar cities, all of the <a href="https://realestate.usnews.com/places/rankings/fastest-growing-places" title="Fastest-Growing Places in the U.S. in 2022-2023" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">fastest growing places</a> are in other regions. Sam's response below.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>No, literally what I would do is make a venture capital fund, get really good GPs [general partners] to do the advice, and fund the companies to come be in St. Louis.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>St. Louis has lost momentum, and there has been the talent drain that you would expect from that. So I would spend all of the money trying to get a few really interesting, high-growth startups that I was confident in to go move to the city of St. Louis and build enough of an ecosystem around them to make them successful and let that regenerate the talent pool in much of the city.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>I would just invest in them on the condition they move to St. Louis. We talked earlier about the importance of a network effect. Rather than do this for one or two companies at a time, I would do it for enough at once, get them all in one part of the city to form something like what Y Combinator has done here.</p>
</blockquote>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Let Milwaukee Build</title>
        <author>
            <name>Colin White</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/let-milwaukee-build.html"/>
        <id>https://MkeCountyBlog.com/let-milwaukee-build.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/28/mitchellBuilding.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="UWM"/>
            <category term="Old Buildings"/>
            <category term="Historic Designation"/>
            <category term="Development"/>

        <updated>2022-06-10T15:35:44-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/28/mitchellBuilding.jpg" alt="Very ornate Mitchell Building in downtown Milwaukee." />
                    Whenever I go to the city I end up looking about at the old pre-1940's buildings; especially the grand, stone&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/28/mitchellBuilding.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Very ornate Mitchell Building in downtown Milwaukee." /></p>
                <p>Whenever I go to the city I end up looking about at the old pre-1940's buildings; especially the grand, stone buildings like above. At the same time, when people purchase one of them, they have the right to decide what is done with it; it is theirs and not ours. The process Milwaukee uses to designate buildings historic has become a tool used to slow new development rather then protect historically significant, unique buildings. Every building has an interesting history but the vast majority should not be protected.</p>
<p>I propose only the owner should be allowed to initiate the historic designation process. If a building is sold without having been designated, only the new owner may decide to submit it. One way to lower building costs and maintain sufficient quantities of affordable housing is to maintain a simple, predictable set of rules. When we allow any random person to trigger a historic designation or require a committee to approve renovation or new building designs, the delays and special material costs lead directly to more expensive housing for everybody.</p>
<p>Potential purchasers or renovators of old buildings are frightened off by the high costs associated with historic renovations and the difficulty they will encounter receiving approvals. The owner may want to use a $1,000 aluminum clad window but the local committee requires a period appropriate wood window that costs $8,000. Buildings that could be renovated and utilized will fall into disrepair and eventually being demolished.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.jsonline.com/story/news/education/2020/01/13/uwm-plans-raze-original-columbia-hospital-despite-some-opposition/2827029001/" title="After a decade in limbo, UWM plans to demolish part of historic Columbia complex" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Devi Shastri of the Milwaukee Journal Sentinel reported</a> the University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee purchased the non-historically designated Columbia St. Mary's Hospital complex in 2010. Emphasis added by me.</p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong>The six-building Columbia complex, which spans more than four city blocks, spent years sitting largely empty</strong> since the purchase — the victim of a lack of public funding. In recent years, <strong>that's changed for all but one of the buildings.</strong><br>Renovating and putting back into use that building, which is the original hospital building and is known as "A Building," has become "infeasible," Geoff Hurtado, UWM's associate vice chancellor for facilities planning and management said. </p>
</blockquote>
<p>UWM repurposed 5 of the 6 original buildings but determined the cost was too great to save the original Columbia Hospital; In January 2020 they announced their plan to for demolition. They spent more then two years pushing back against a historic designation submitted by a random individual whom no longer lives in the neighborhood. The person remembers the building fondly from childhood and therefore feels the building should be protected and the owner's right to demolish restrained.</p>
<p>The current system presumes an owner's cost-benefit analysis is unacceptable criteria for making decisions and that they lack a desire to preserve the character of their own building. Therefore the designation process is essential for protecting buildings on behalf of locals that enjoy their appearance. During the 1960's many historic buildings were cleared to make way for highways, apartments, office buildings, and dorms. A nostalgic view of these long gone places creates a desire to preserve what remains but we must not allow our personal reminiscence to block growth and progress that can drive Milwaukee forward and create badly needed prosperity within the community.</p>
<p>View buildings like restaurants; the interior of a restaurant changes from occupant to occupant; if their funds are tight they will make small changes to the previous theme; maybe buy new tables and hang different pictures on the wall. If the venture is well funded they might make a more dramatic change or attempt to restore the look to it's original splendor. Also common is for a successful restaurant to outgrow their space and move into a larger building at a more attractive location; see <a href="https://onmilwaukee.com/articles/odd-duck-moving-to-walkers-point" title="After nearly a decade, Odd Duck is making a big move" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Odd Duck for a recent example</a>. Odd Duck moved to a more visible, higher capacity place while their old space is now welcoming <a href="https://milwaukeerecord.com/food-drink/tulum-latin-gastropub-to-open-in-former-odd-duck-space-april-26/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Tulum Latin Gastropub</a>.</p>
<p>Within a single area restaurants are big or small, fancy or relaxed, cheap or expensive, with many differing cuisines. The variety is part of what makes a desirable neighborhood. Observe in Milwaukee the makeup of the most in demand neighborhoods like Brady Street, the Lower East Side, East Town, the Third Ward, the Water Tower Neighborhood, Bay View, or Wauwatosa; new high rises exist comfortably next door to 130 year old houses of many different geographic architectural styles.</p>
<p>Delaying new, often higher density, development drives up the cost of housing and makes it more difficult for lower income families to move into neighborhoods that provide the most opportunities. If a new apartment building is constructed near an older apartment building rents of the older building will likely decrease since the newer building will draw some tenants away. When there are more empty apartments and homes, their prices decrease thus allowing new people to move in. The most desirable buildings will likely maintain a higher price but the majority will need to adjust to the ebbs and flows of demand.</p>
<p>Recent Examples of Delays</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://urbanmilwaukee.com/2022/01/04/eyes-on-milwaukee-bay-view-homes-lose-historic-protection/" title="Bay View Homes Lose Historic Protection" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bay View Homes Lose Historic Protection</a></li>
<li><a href="https://urbanmilwaukee.com/2021/09/13/eyes-on-milwaukee-connaughtons-company-withdraws-brewers-hill-plan-for-now/" title="Connaughton’s Company Withdraws Brewers Hill Plan. For Now" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Connaughton’s Company Withdraws Brewers Hill Plan. For Now</a></li>
<li><a href="https://urbanmilwaukee.com/2019/10/31/eyes-on-milwaukee-bucks-players-development-faces-delay/" title="Bucks Player’s Development Faces Delay" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Bucks Player’s Development Faces Delay</a></li>
<li><a href="https://urbanmilwaukee.com/2021/03/19/friday-photos-new-east-side-homes/" title="New East Side Homes" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">New East Side Homes</a></li>
<li><a href="https://urbanmilwaukee.com/2020/12/16/eyes-on-milwaukee-forest-home-library-not-historic-clinic-approved/" title="Forest Home Library Not Historic, Clinic Approved" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Forest Home Library Not Historic, Clinic Approved</a></li>
<li><a href="https://urbanmilwaukee.com/2019/05/07/eyes-on-milwaukee-council-says-marcus-center-not-historic/" title="Council Says Marcus Center Not Historic" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Council Says Marcus Center Not Historic</a></li>
</ul>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Feedbin, Feedly, &amp; Inoreader - How Two Feed Readers Forgot The Fundamentals</title>
        <author>
            <name>Colin White</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/feedbin-feedly-and-inoreader-how-two-feed-readers-forgot-the-fundamentals.html"/>
        <id>https://MkeCountyBlog.com/feedbin-feedly-and-inoreader-how-two-feed-readers-forgot-the-fundamentals.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/27/donald-giannatti-8NYX8bVvPiQ-unsplash.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="RSS"/>
            <category term="Podcast"/>
            <category term="Open Source"/>
            <category term="Feedly"/>
            <category term="Feedbin"/>
            <category term="Feed Reader"/>
            <category term="AI"/>

        <updated>2022-03-15T16:37:57-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/27/donald-giannatti-8NYX8bVvPiQ-unsplash.jpg" alt="A single Aspen tree stands brilliant against a sea of green." />
                    Early in 2020 I made the shift from self-hosting with Tiny Tiny RSS then FreshRSS to buying an annual Feedbin&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/27/donald-giannatti-8NYX8bVvPiQ-unsplash.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="A single Aspen tree stands brilliant against a sea of green." /></p>
                <p>Early in 2020 I made the shift from self-hosting with Tiny Tiny RSS then FreshRSS to buying an annual <a href="https://feedbin.com" title="Feedbin" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Feedbin</a> subscription. The features I like with Feedbin include,</p>
<ul>
<li>Proxies all remote connections so a bunch of advertisers can't follow me around the internet. Overall a <a href="https://feedbin.com/blog/2018/09/11/private-by-default/" title="Private by Default" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">strong design emphasis on privacy</a>.</li>
<li>Visually pleasant to use and read; I especially enjoy the smooth slide transition when swiping left and right between the article list and the article.</li>
<li>Fantastic podcast support.
<ul>
<li>You listen in the app and can read other articles while it plays in the background.</li>
<li>Playing position is tracked across devices. Start playing on your phone and switch to the desktop. Easy!</li>
<li>There is a 'Recently Played' section in addition to the more common 'Recently Read' section.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Open source - not a requirement but I like to encourage it where possible.</li>
</ul>
<p>After reading that <a href="https://marginalrevolution.com/?s=feedly" title="Marginal Revolution Results For “feedly”" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Tyler uses Feedly</a> I started to think the grass may be greener and started trying out the competition. <a href="https://feedly.com" title="Feedly" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Feedly</a> is beautiful and has some features that cause it to stand out from the pack.</p>
<ul>
<li>Uses AI to highlight key points within an article which can be a big time saver.</li>
<li>Uses AI to create a 'priority' list which improves as you give feedback. (😎 Very cool!)</li>
<li>Customize every little thing.</li>
<li>Also proxies images.</li>
<li>Can create a feed from websites without a Atom/RSS feed.</li>
</ul>
<p>Feedly is pricey in relation to other feed readers (Annual as of 3/15/2022: Feedly $144; Inoreader $69.96; Feedbin $50) but I believe the extra features may justify it. If you need or want to process tons of articles in an efficient way, Feedly is a great way to bring  what you actually want to read to the top. However, the reason I canceled Feedly is they automatically mark articles older then 30 days read which is very annoying with podcasts or new feeds that you may want to read from the beginning. I was impressed with their customer support as they issued a full refund by 7am the day after an 11pm request with no hassle at all.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.inoreader.com/" title="Inoreader" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Inoreader</a> is another popular choice with a great interface and many ways to tailor the look and functionality to individual tastes. I spent very little time with it but the functionality seems similar to Feedly and the price is considerably lower. Their refund process was also very simple with a morning refund after an evening email.</p>
<p>In the end Feedbin remained the clear champ for my reading/listening flow. The other two readers podcast support is weak and the shiny features weren't quite enough to overcome the flaws in their basic functionality. In another year or so that may not be the case.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>To The Domes!</title>
        <author>
            <name>Colin White</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/to-the-domes.html"/>
        <id>https://MkeCountyBlog.com/to-the-domes.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/26/domes3.jpeg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Winter"/>
            <category term="Tropical Dome"/>
            <category term="Trains"/>
            <category term="Photography"/>
            <category term="Mitchell Park Domes"/>
            <category term="Milwaukee County"/>
            <category term="Desert Dome"/>
            <category term="Cupcakes"/>

        <updated>2022-02-13T14:53:31-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/26/domes3.jpeg" alt="A view of the garden dome with two domes in the distance." />
                    I last ventured to the Mitchell Park Domes several years ago to experience the very underwhelming and misleadingly named Cupcake&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/26/domes3.jpeg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="A view of the garden dome with two domes in the distance." /></p>
                <p>I last ventured to the Mitchell Park Domes several years ago to experience the very underwhelming and misleadingly named Cupcake Fest (only one cupcake vendor 😭!) My home has since added a son and my in-laws so Jenny and I decided to help them break up their first winter with a trip to the domes. The popular <a href="https://milwaukeedomes.org/show-dome-exhibits" title="Rotating Exhibits / Events" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">train show</a> is here and coronavirus restrictions limit the capacity so the domes are quite spacious. A few observations follow.</p>
<ul>
<li>Jumping directly from months of dull-colored winter scenery to brightly colored flowers without spring in between or travel is disorienting initially. My body was slightly unnerved.</li>
<li>The structure of the domes looks better in photographs then in person.</li>
<li>The Desert Dome is not as warm as I remember (maybe 70°F.) Perhaps my memory is wrong or the tight county budget forced them to cool it down?</li>
<li>The trees are more enjoyable then the plants. Trees draw attention upwards which allows for the simultaneous viewing of treetops and the geodesic dome. Perhaps I'm lazy and enjoy not having to focus too closely on the smaller, tucked away plants.</li>
<li>Capturing the massive scale of trees is difficult with photography. I had the same issue on a trip to Hawaii where I failed to capture the incredible largeness of a banyan tree.</li>
<li>The Tropical Dome is the best; a higher proportion of exotic plants and a temperature that required the removal of my coat.</li>
</ul>
<p>All said and done it was a much more satisfying trip.</p>
<div class="gallery-wrapper"><div class="gallery"  data-is-empty="false" data-columns="3">
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/26/gallery/domes1.jpg" data-size="1200x1600"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/26/gallery/domes1-thumbnail.webp" alt="The Show Dome with barren trees visible outside." width="720" height="960"></a>
<figcaption>Not convinced it's winter? Just take a look outside 😉. © Colin White</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/26/gallery/domes6.jpeg" data-size="1200x1600"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/26/gallery/domes6-thumbnail.webp" alt="A spiky desert plant." width="720" height="960"></a>
<figcaption>Spiky. © Colin White</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/26/gallery/domes5.jpeg" data-size="1200x1600"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/26/gallery/domes5-thumbnail.webp" alt="A view upwards towards to top of the dome with treetops visible." width="720" height="960"></a>
<figcaption>© Colin White</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/26/gallery/domes4.jpeg" data-size="1600x1200"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/26/gallery/domes4-thumbnail.webp" alt="The lush tropical trees and plants of the Tropical Dome." width="720" height="540"></a>
<figcaption>The lush, beautiful Tropical Dome. © Colin White</figcaption>
</figure>
</div></div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The Role Of Bail On Milwaukee Crime Increases</title>
        <author>
            <name>Colin White</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/the-role-of-bail-on-milwaukee-crime-increases.html"/>
        <id>https://MkeCountyBlog.com/the-role-of-bail-on-milwaukee-crime-increases.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/25/MilwaukeeCountyCourthouse.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Waukesha"/>
            <category term="WTMJ"/>
            <category term="Milwaukee County"/>
            <category term="Mary Triggiano"/>
            <category term="John Chisholm"/>
            <category term="Jeff Wagner"/>
            <category term="Crime"/>
            <category term="Bail"/>

        <updated>2021-12-14T21:00:05-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/25/MilwaukeeCountyCourthouse.jpg" alt="Milwaukee County Courthouse east side. Tall columned limestone building." />
                    The Jeff Wagner Show on WTMJ recently discussed an increase in crime over the last two years that Jeff attributes&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/25/MilwaukeeCountyCourthouse.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Milwaukee County Courthouse east side. Tall columned limestone building." /></p>
                <p>The Jeff Wagner Show on WTMJ recently discussed an increase in crime over the last two years that Jeff attributes to District Attorney John Chisholm’s election in 2007 and the policies his office created that release more defendants on bail. He seems to relate these policies directly to the spike in crime Milwaukee has experienced in car thefts, shootings, and general lawlessness.</p>
<p>The latest discussion of this topic was sparked by the individual that used his car to kill and injure multiple people during Waukesha’s annual Christmas parade. Jeff said that many of his contacts in law enforcement and the legal system backup his idea that the ease of gaining release for defendants is correlated with the jump in crime. We can sum up his argument as releasing suspected criminals on bail frees them to terrorize law-abiding citizens of Milwaukee County and the surrounding suburbs.</p>
<p>People charged with a crime are considered innocent until proven guilty. The stated goal of bail in Milwaukee is to incentivize defendants to show up for their court date so the bail amount is determined based on their likelihood of doing so. Jeff believes this law should be changed to include more consideration for the safety of the community.</p>
<p>In a recent <a href="https://www.jsonline.com/story/news/local/milwaukee/2021/12/02/john-chisholm-discuss-low-bail-given-man-charged-waukesha-christmas-parade-attack-darrell-brooks/8814614002/" title="'A mistake:' Chisholm, chief judge explain low bail given to Waukesha parade suspect in earlier case" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Milwaukee Journal Sentinel article</a>, Chisholm said that the low bail set for the individual in question was the result of an overburdened, somewhat new staff member determining bail prior to viewing the risk assessment. The court commissioner overseeing the trial that had access to the risk assessment also allowed this person to slip by with $1,000 bail.</p>
<p>According to Chief Judge Mary Triggiano, the courts currently have a backlog of 1,600 felony cases and a misdemeanor backlog of about 3,100 cases owing in part to the court shutting down and restricting services during 2020; Milwaukee’s large upswing in violent crime most likely is also a contributor.</p>
<p>It is difficult to judge Jeff’s argument without some sort of statistics to gauge how widespread the problem is; he spoke of two separate cases that made the news but that doesn’t give us a view of the overall picture. Unfortunately the county doesn’t appear to track this information. It would be immensely useful for the county to track,</p>
<ol>
<li>The number of defendants released on bail.</li>
<li>The type of crime they are accused of.</li>
<li>The price of granted bail.</li>
<li>If arrested after posting bail, the type of crime they are accused of.</li>
<li>Whether they are convicted of the accused crimes.</li>
</ol>
<p>Without the above information we are somewhat limited in determining the scope of the problem. What we can observe is if Milwaukee’s <a href="https://www.city-data.com/crime/crime-Milwaukee-Wisconsin.html" title="City-Data.com: Crime rate in Milwaukee, Wisconsin" target="null">crime rate</a> increased after Chisolm took office. During his 14 years in office there have been less than 100 murders in all but 6 years; still horrific but this this is an improvement over the 100+ homicides regularly seen since the 1990’s. The crime rate also dropped substantially reaching a nadir in 2019 prior to the 2020 pandemic, protests, riots and massive increase in violent crime around the United States. Looking at the <a href="https://city.milwaukee.gov/police/Information-Services/Crime-Maps-and-Statistics" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Milwaukee Police Department crime map</a>, 2019 saw a grand total of 23,492 crimes. 2021 appears likely to surpass 31,000 while most likely breaking 2020’s record for murders.</p>
<p>The current bail system seems to already take into consideration a person’s past criminal conduct; the Waukesha tragedy to me seems like the result of an error resulting from an overextended system. However even if flooded with cases, if the DA and judicial system are regularly unable to prevent releasing violent people from custody then that absolutely demands some significant adjustments to the status quo.</p>
<p>I feel confident that Chisholm staying or leaving office will make little difference towards fixing what ails Milwaukee. As of now, 50 years of policy-making has failed to make a real dent in American crime; sure there have been significant shifts over the years but the overall culture of criminality remains an ever present societal issue. Until the towns and neighborhoods where the vast majority of these crimes are committed find some way towards incremental improvements we will continue to see more of the same. Why has this become the standard way of life for so many people? Why have so many communities degraded to this point and what can we <em>really</em> do to fix it.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Linux Devices Require User Patience</title>
        <author>
            <name>Colin White</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/linux-devices-require-user-patience.html"/>
        <id>https://MkeCountyBlog.com/linux-devices-require-user-patience.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/24/wesley-pribadi-iS1NV9yN0Lg-unsplash.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="system76"/>
            <category term="Thelio Major"/>
            <category term="Purism"/>
            <category term="Patience"/>
            <category term="Linux"/>
            <category term="Librem 5"/>
            <category term="Expectations"/>

        <updated>2021-09-27T15:26:08-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/24/wesley-pribadi-iS1NV9yN0Lg-unsplash.jpg" alt="Many penguins standing on a rock in a mostly dark space." />
                    February 2020 I bought a system76 Thelio Major AMD desktop computer to replace a 10 year old desktop I had&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/24/wesley-pribadi-iS1NV9yN0Lg-unsplash.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Many penguins standing on a rock in a mostly dark space." /></p>
                <p>February 2020 I bought a <a href="https://system76.com/desktops" title="system76 Thelio Major Desktops" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">system76 Thelio Major AMD desktop computer</a> to replace a 10 year old desktop I had built myself. I was pretty happy with the purchase until the computer started regularly locking up requiring a hard restart to resolve. Later, an update to system76’s software or perhaps the Linux kernel caused the fans to always run at full speed creating a very loud box despite their pitch of being designed to be extremely quiet.</p>
<p>This week after a Fedora kernel and system76 update, the fans once again quieted down; the locking up still happens sporadically (I consider this a problem with AMD and not system76) but otherwise the computer is now functioning as I originally expected.</p>
<p>This expensive purchase was meant to provide a hassle free decade of computer use but gave me a noisy, locking mess instead. As with any Linux problem, I reported it and  patiently waited for a resolution. Unlike Purism which focuses on using older, open hardware, System76 has a few more bugs due to selling the latest and greatest. If a user is patient then these problems are eventually fixed which I am glad to say has happened for the Thelio.</p>
<p>For Linux users, the ideal device often takes time to reach its fulfillment. This kerfuffle with my computer reminded me of the <a href="https://puri.sm/products/librem-5/" title="Librem 5 Device Page" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Purism Librem 5 phone</a> which has mostly been sitting around collecting dust. The phone is the result of a very ambitious project by Purism to create an open, private, Linux phone with hardware kill-switches. My phone came November 2020 and has received steady operating system and software updates resulting in a fairly smooth user experience (nowhere near Apple and Google but let us maintain realistic expectations.) If the phone is ever certified for use with VoLTE I will give it a try as my regular phone.</p>
<p>Expectations for this sort of low volume devices need to be set properly for the purchaser. With the Librem 5 I expected a phone that would be unusable for a year or two after receiving it; I get to enjoy watching the ecosystem grow for Linux phones and read about Purism's contribution to open software and hardware development. With the Thelio Major I expected a mostly stable system upon first boot; this was the impression I absorbed from their website. My incorrect assumption lowered my opinion of their devices despite their helpful support department's best efforts to pinpoint and (unsuccessfully) resolve the problems.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Speedway Punished For Being Repeatedly Robbed</title>
        <author>
            <name>Colin White</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/speedway-punished-for-being-repeatedly-robbed.html"/>
        <id>https://MkeCountyBlog.com/speedway-punished-for-being-repeatedly-robbed.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/23/maxim-hopman-PEJHULxUHZs-unsplash.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Speedway"/>
            <category term="Milwaukee Common Council"/>
            <category term="MPD"/>
            <category term="Licensing"/>
            <category term="Crime"/>
            <category term="Alderwoman Chantia Lewis"/>
            <category term="Alderman Mark Borkowski"/>

        <updated>2021-05-26T14:11:41-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/23/maxim-hopman-PEJHULxUHZs-unsplash.jpg" alt="Shadow on a home wall showing a gun pointed at a person with raised hands" />
                    Earlier this year during a licensing hearing the Milwaukee City Council made a bizarre decision essentially blaming the owners of&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/23/maxim-hopman-PEJHULxUHZs-unsplash.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Shadow on a home wall showing a gun pointed at a person with raised hands" /></p>
                <p>Earlier this year <a href="https://milwaukee.granicus.com/MediaPlayer.php?view_id=2&amp;clip_id=2696&amp;meta_id=2830638" title="Video of Licences Committee Meeting" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">during a licensing hearing</a> the Milwaukee City Council made <a href="https://urbanmilwaukee.com/2021/05/06/city-hall-bay-view-speedway-must-close-early-after-robbery-string/" title="Urban Milwaukee: Bay View Speedway Must Close Early After Robbery String" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">a bizarre decision</a> essentially blaming the owners of an Oklahoma Ave Speedway for being robbed multiple times during a month.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Quite frankly, Speedway, this location has utilized the resources of the sixth MPD district way, way too much. You have abused that privilege.</p>
</blockquote>
<address class="align-center"><em>Alderman Mark Borkowski</em></address>
<p>What a confusing notion; being unwillingly robbed by others is abusing MPD’s resources and should be punished. Is there lighting outside? Are there security cameras? Do they have a sign in their window inviting criminal activity? If they follow general best practices for gas stations or commit to doing so then I fail to see how this is anything other than the council attempting to be seen as taking swift action to address a local crime problem. Since they have little ability to actually reduce crime, the victimized business is forcing to close earlier instead.</p>
<p>The Council seems to view the issue as follows,</p>
<ol>
<li>Speedway is open from 12am until 5am.</li>
<li>People are regularily robbing Speedway around those hours.</li>
<li>If we close Speedway during the night, the criminals won’t have a business to rob.</li>
<li>The criminals will instead do something other than commit crime.</li>
</ol>
<p>My view of the issue is as follows,</p>
<ol>
<li>There are people regularly robbing a local business.</li>
<li>We should protect the business by finding and punishing these individuals.</li>
<li>We should work with the police department to determine why this area is attracting robberies.</li>
<li>We should attempt to address discovered issues without harming local residents and businesses.</li>
</ol>
<p>It can be argued that the Common Council are using the only tools available to them in an attempt to address crime in this neighborhood. The often repeated mistake from government bodies is believing that they are responsible for correcting any and all societal problems when in fact, they have a very limited ability to do so. Individuals and communities create and must resolve their own problems; the Common Council is unable to do so. Harming an innocent business should not be the byproduct of this limitation.</p>
<p>Alderwoman Chantia Lewis said that restricting the Speedway’s hours in aldermanic district 9 alleviated similar issues there.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>As an alder who has a Speedway in her district and seen the alleviation of a lot of issues in the district when the Speedway isn’t open over night I would move renewal of the food dealer’s license but non-renewal of the extended hours based off of the police report, aldermanic testimony and district 9 knowledge.</p>
</blockquote>
<p class="align-center"><em>Alderwoman Chantia Lewis</em></p>
<p>However, <a href="https://city.milwaukee.gov/police/Information-Services/Crime-Maps-and-Statistics" title="MPD Crime Map &amp; Statistics" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">district 9 crime statistics</a> for the last few years show a significant increase in robberies. Between 2019 and 2020 robbery increased by 43% from 88 to 126. Year to date robbery has again increased 3%. Late night businesses are not the issue that needs addressing and robbery statistics do not appear to backup the alderwoman’s claims about the results of limitations placed on her district's Speedway.</p>
<p>Further east on opposing corners of E Oklahoma Ave are a Mobil and BP gas station. I wonder why the Speedway is a regular target while the others are ignored. Speedway appears to be the only business open late on nearby blocks; perhaps that is related? Could Humboldt Park directly across the street be the issue?</p>
<p>Understandably, none of these questions are answered in the article; however, after purchasing bullet proof glass ($100,000) and offering to change their security guard schedule from three days to everyday, Speedway has now been punished (for being robbed) by having their extended hour license revoked meaning they will now lose their right to operate from 12-5am despite MPD writing a letter in their favor.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Bally Sports, Please Shrink The Score Box</title>
        <author>
            <name>Colin White</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/bally-sports-please-shrink-the-score-box.html"/>
        <id>https://MkeCountyBlog.com/bally-sports-please-shrink-the-score-box.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/22/sportsScoresEasierFoundOnPhone.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Score Box/Ticker"/>
            <category term="Fox Sports"/>
            <category term="Bucks"/>
            <category term="Brewers"/>
            <category term="Bally Total Fitness"/>
            <category term="Bally Sports"/>

        <updated>2021-05-26T14:11:50-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/22/sportsScoresEasierFoundOnPhone.jpg" alt="Basketball players in Hong Kong with a large box obstructing the lower 10% of the picture." />
                    The clock struck midnight April 1st and Fox Sports Wisconsin magically transformed into Bally Sports. The name “Bally” returns memories&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/22/sportsScoresEasierFoundOnPhone.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Basketball players in Hong Kong with a large box obstructing the lower 10% of the picture." /></p>
                <p>The clock struck midnight April 1<sup>st </sup>and Fox Sports Wisconsin magically transformed into Bally Sports. The name “Bally” returns memories of Bally Total Fitness; a fitness center I never went to with locations around Milwaukee that apparently <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bally_Total_Fitness#Investigations_and_controversies" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">became very shady</a> before going bankrupt in 2016. While I held a neutral opinion of Fox Sports overall, among the various sport broadcasters they had the best score box and provided a pleasant viewing experience for Bucks and Brewers games.</p>
<p>Their graphics left space all around the score box leaving it to float towards the bottom of the screen; thus removing the “lets eat up 1/5 of the screen found elsewhere (I’m looking at you ESPN.) I see no need for the Fox Sports and Bucks logo in the upper right but what can you do?</p>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center" ><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/22/foxsportsBucks-2.jpg" alt="Milwaukee Bucks game as broadcasted on Fox Sports Wisconsin." width="1151" height="650" sizes="100vw" srcset="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/22/responsive/foxsportsBucks-2-xs.webp 300w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/22/responsive/foxsportsBucks-2-sm.webp 480w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/22/responsive/foxsportsBucks-2-md.webp 768w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/22/responsive/foxsportsBucks-2-lg.webp 1024w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/22/responsive/foxsportsBucks-2-xl.webp 1360w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/22/responsive/foxsportsBucks-2-2xl.webp 1600w">
<figcaption >
<div class="css-1dbjc4n r-14gqq1x"><a href="https://twitter.com/BallySportWI/status/962147173604274176" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"> </a>
<div class="css-1dbjc4n r-1wbh5a2 r-dnmrzs r-1ny4l3l"><a href="https://twitter.com/BallySportWI/status/962147173604274176" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"> </a>
<div class="css-1dbjc4n r-18u37iz r-1wbh5a2"><a href="https://twitter.com/BallySportWI/status/962147173604274176" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"> </a>
<div class="css-901oao css-bfa6kz r-m0bqgq r-18u37iz r-1qd0xha r-a023e6 r-16dba41 r-rjixqe r-bcqeeo r-qvutc0" dir="ltr"><span class="css-901oao css-16my406 r-poiln3 r-bcqeeo r-qvutc0"><span class="css-901oao css-16my406 r-poiln3 r-bcqeeo r-qvutc0">Bledsoe with the steal and finish. ©<a href="https://twitter.com/BallySportWI/status/962147173604274176" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@BallySportWI</a> </span></span></div>
<a href="https://twitter.com/BallySportWI/status/962147173604274176" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"> </a></div>
<a href="https://twitter.com/BallySportWI/status/962147173604274176" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"> </a></div>
<a href="https://twitter.com/BallySportWI/status/962147173604274176" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"> </a></div>
</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>A similar display existed for the Brewers; all of the information I want provided within a tidy, compact box that stays out of the game's way and avoids unnecessary distraction.</p>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center" ><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/22/foxSportsBrewers.jpg" alt="Milwaukee Brewers game as presented by Fox Sports Wisconsin." width="1161" height="650" sizes="100vw" srcset="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/22/responsive/foxSportsBrewers-xs.webp 300w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/22/responsive/foxSportsBrewers-sm.webp 480w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/22/responsive/foxSportsBrewers-md.webp 768w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/22/responsive/foxSportsBrewers-lg.webp 1024w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/22/responsive/foxSportsBrewers-xl.webp 1360w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/22/responsive/foxSportsBrewers-2xl.webp 1600w">
<figcaption ><span class="css-901oao css-16my406 r-poiln3 r-bcqeeo r-qvutc0"><span class="css-901oao css-16my406 r-poiln3 r-bcqeeo r-qvutc0">@ChristianYelich goes yard for the 16th time this season. <span style="color: var(--text-light-color); font-family: var(--font-base); font-size: 0.70233em; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">©</span><a href="https://twitter.com/BallySportWI/status/1025211771722715137" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@BallySportWI</a></span></span></figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Unfortunately, all was lost during the transition to Bally Sports. They introduced themselves with a big honker of a score box/ticker combo that changes ESPN’s two level score box/ticker into a one level behemoth without reducing used screen space 😖.</p>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center" ><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/22/ballySports.png" alt="Bucks game as presented by Bally Sports. Notice the larger ticker at the bottom." width="1154" height="650" sizes="100vw" srcset="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/22/responsive/ballySports-xs.webp 300w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/22/responsive/ballySports-sm.webp 480w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/22/responsive/ballySports-md.webp 768w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/22/responsive/ballySports-lg.webp 1024w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/22/responsive/ballySports-xl.webp 1360w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/22/responsive/ballySports-2xl.webp 1600w">
<figcaption >I also love how the camera is zoomed in and tilted up so viewers can better see stadium advertisements instead of the floor! © Milwaukee County Blog</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>The color scheme is an improvement over ESPN but I wish the ticker were removed entirely. I’m more interested in seeing the hitters count at all times rather than how the Rockies are doing (Boo Rockies?) The world only needs a single Bally “B” logo on screen at once so how about dropping the upper right corner logos? I know I’m watching the Bucks or Brewers because their logo or name is next to the score so the extra reminder in the corner is superfluous.</p>
<p>Hopefully some day Bally will revert back to the more pleasant presentation of March 31 and I can get back to screaming at the Fox Sports Go app on Apple TV that crashes constantly and requires me to login to my account every time the Bucks take a shot. I am legitimately very excited to see Bally Sports' promised upgrade to their apps. They have a very low bar to step over.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Time Will Tell for Internxt</title>
        <author>
            <name>Colin White</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/time-will-tell-for-internxt.html"/>
        <id>https://MkeCountyBlog.com/time-will-tell-for-internxt.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/19/cookie-the-pom-gySMaocSdqs-unsplash.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Services"/>
            <category term="Open Source"/>
            <category term="Internxt"/>
            <category term="Encryption"/>

        <updated>2021-05-26T14:13:11-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/19/cookie-the-pom-gySMaocSdqs-unsplash.jpg" alt="Pomeranian dog wearing glasses while looking at an iPad." />
                    I came across Internxt while looking into ProtonDrive as a supplement or potential replacement of Nextcloud. Internxt further strengthens remote,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/19/cookie-the-pom-gySMaocSdqs-unsplash.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Pomeranian dog wearing glasses while looking at an iPad." /></p>
                <p>I came across <a href="https://internxt.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Internxt</a> while looking into ProtonDrive as a supplement or potential replacement of Nextcloud. Internxt further strengthens remote, encrypted file storage by breaking individual files into little pieces (sharding) and storing them on different servers. With common file storage options like Dropbox, Google Drive, Nextcloud, and others; if someone steals a file from the server (lets assume it's encrypted) they can theoretically decrypt it (over a remarkably long period of time or with a massive amount of processing power.) Stealing a complete file from Internxt however would require a thief to solve the world's most complicated jigsaw puzzle. Puzzle pieces are hidden in piles of unrelated puzzle pieces in multiple places all over  the world (good luck!)</p>
<p>I purchased the 2TB lifetime subscription to support the company building the product. It is currently too lacking in features to be used efficiently on a daily basis so my hope is that one day they produce a better product. All of the clients are in various forms of development so until they mature more it is not a particularly useful tool.</p>
<p>My primary hesitation on spending money on their product was their lack of documentation describing their security model and system design. ProtonDrive, which is being developed by the people behind <a href="https://protonmail.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ProtonMail</a>, did a much better job presenting the <a href="https://protonmail.com/blog/protondrive-security/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">architecture of their security system</a>. To Internxt's credit, all of their code is already <a href="https://github.com/internxt" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">open source</a> unlike Proton which generally creates, releases and later open sources their products. However, undocumented and unreviewed source code provides non-technical users minimal assurance.</p>
<p>Internxt seems more focused on marketing that compares themselves with competitors than in demonstrating the security of their design. My hope is that they spend 2021 improving their functionality, releasing desktop and mobile clients, and then have a reputable company perform an audit of their code. Smaller teams have to choose where their limited time is focused in order to grow and become successful; as a advocate of open source tech I am content to wait and see how things progress. It is understandable why Internxt has chosen their current path and I have high hopes that with time it will develop into a valuable tool that people around the world utilize on a daily basis; today it's just not ready.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Campus Buildings Then &amp; Now</title>
        <author>
            <name>Colin White</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/campus-buildings-then-and-now.html"/>
        <id>https://MkeCountyBlog.com/campus-buildings-then-and-now.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/thenAndNow.jpeg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Wgema Campus"/>
            <category term="Potawatomi"/>
            <category term="Concordia College"/>
            <category term="CUW"/>

        <updated>2020-12-30T09:02:37-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/thenAndNow.jpeg" alt="Black and white picture of 4 story brick dormitory in the 1920&#x27;s. Old car and motorcycle parked out front." />
                    Desktop: Click picture to enlarge it; use keyboard's arrow keys to move around. Clicking on the enlarged picture will let&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/thenAndNow.jpeg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Black and white picture of 4 story brick dormitory in the 1920&#x27;s. Old car and motorcycle parked out front." /></p>
                <p><strong>Desktop: </strong>Click picture to enlarge it; use keyboard's arrow keys to move around. Clicking on the enlarged picture will let you zoom in.</p>
<p><strong>Mobile: </strong>Click picture to enlarge it; swipe back and forth to move forward and back. Tap image to hide text. Feel free to zoom in on pictures.</p>
<div class="gallery-wrapper"><div class="gallery"  data-is-empty="false" data-columns="4">
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/01.jpg" data-size="3024x4032"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/01-thumbnail.webp" alt="Trinity Lutheran Church; tall steeple in the front. Weathered, dark cream city brick covered church built on a street corner." width="720" height="960"></a>
<figcaption>In 1881 Concordia College held their first class in the basement of Trinity Lutheran Church at 9th and Highland Avenue in downtown Milwaukee. Image © Colin White</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/02-1890-Baists-Property-Atlas.jpg" data-size="1073x1500"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/02-1890-Baists-Property-Atlas-thumbnail.webp" alt="Old multicolored map depicting the original Concordia College buildings. The map is somewhat distorted." width="720" height="1007"></a>
<figcaption>The following year they moved west to their new campus. As shown in the 1890 Baist's Property Atlas, the campus borders were North 31st Street, North 33rd Street, West State Street and West Wells Street. It appears that at the time the Milwaukee &amp; Watertown Plank Road still ran along the northern edge of campus. Image © Milwaukee County Land Information Office</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/03-1894-Sanbourn-Fire-Insurance-Map.jpg" data-size="1155x1500"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/03-1894-Sanbourn-Fire-Insurance-Map-thumbnail.webp" alt="A different map from 1894 that shows complete building outlines for the campus." width="720" height="935"></a>
<figcaption>A non-distorted view of the campus buildings courtesy of the 1894 Sanborn Fire Insurance Map. Image © Milwaukee County Land Information Office</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/04-1910-Sanbourn-Fire-Insurance-Map.jpg" data-size="1215x1500"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/04-1910-Sanbourn-Fire-Insurance-Map-thumbnail.webp" alt="A map from 1910 that shows complete building outlines for the campus." width="720" height="889"></a>
<figcaption>The 1910 Sanborn Map presents more development in the area as the plank road was removed and more homes were built. Image © Milwaukee County Land Information Office</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/05-highlight-Final.jpg" data-size="1867x1500"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/05-highlight-Final-thumbnail.webp" alt="An aerial view from the 70's with an outline around the campus boundaries and the Miller Brewing logo on the left; Marquette logo on the right." width="720" height="578"></a>
<figcaption>The Concordia College campus (highlighted in blue) is 5 blocks east of the Miller Brewery and 13 blocks west of Marquette University's western edge. Image © Colin White; © Concordia University Wisconsin; © Molson Coors; © Marquette University</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/06-hamman.jpg" data-size="1945x1500"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/06-hamman-thumbnail.webp" alt="Black &amp; white portrait of an elderly man wearing a suit and tie. His head is bald on top." width="720" height="555"></a>
<figcaption>Emil Hamman was the chair and professor of mathematics and science at the college. He served as interim president from 1882-1885. Image © Concordia University Wisconsin</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/10-loeber-2.jpg" data-size="991x1500"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/10-loeber-2-thumbnail.webp" alt="Black &amp; white portrait of a middle-aged man wearing a suit and bow tie. He has a large bulbous beard with no mustache." width="720" height="1090"></a>
<figcaption>Chr. Loeber, the son of a Concordia founder named Henry Loeber, served as president from 1885-1893. Recent students will recognize this name from Loeber Hall at Concordia University Wisconsin's campus in Mequon. Image © Concordia University Wisconsin</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/06.jpg" data-size="4032x2300"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/06-thumbnail.webp" alt="A picture of the campus today on a clear, winter day. There is a long 3 story brick building to the left; another complex of two 3 story buildings starting in the middle. In front are fields." width="720" height="411"></a>
<figcaption>In 1990, seven years after Concordia College left for Mequon, the Forest County Potawatomi Community purchased the land after which they leased it to the Indian Community School. After the school relocated to Franklin in 2007, the Potawatomi evaluated the building conditions and created a long term restoration plan for the newly renamed Wgema Campus. All of the buildings were considered to be in poor shape and required extensive renovations. Recently deceased Potawatomi elder William “Billy” Daniels Jr. blessed and named each building. Daniels had built up the Potawatomi dictionary and was involved in continuing cultural education in the community. Image © Colin White</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/07.0-2.png" data-size="1154x1500"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/07.0-2-thumbnail.webp" alt="Black &amp; white portrait of an elderly man wearing a suit and tie. He wears round eye-glasses and is bald on top." width="720" height="936"></a>
<figcaption>Concordia College president Max Albrecht served from 1893-1921. Afterwards he continued on as a professor of Latin and Greek studies until 1932. Image © Concordia University Wisconsin</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/07.2.jpg" data-size="2667x1500"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/07.2-thumbnail.webp" alt="Black and white photo of a Beaux Arts, brick, 2.5 story building on a snowy, winter day." width="720" height="405"></a>
<figcaption>Recitation Hall was built in 1900 using a design by architect Eugene Liebert. Eventually the building was renamed in honor of the longtime president and professor as Albrecht Hall. Image © Concordia University Wisconsin</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/07.1.jpg" data-size="1892x1500"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/07.1-thumbnail.webp" alt="The same building in summer blocked by trees with a garden out front. The garden, surrounded by a walkway contains flowers that spell out " width="720" height="571"></a>
<figcaption>During the warm season of the year, the Kilbourn entrance to Albrecht Hall had a flower bed in front that spell out "CONCORDIA." Image © Concordia University Wisconsin</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/07.3-recitation.jpg" data-size="1874x1500"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/07.3-recitation-thumbnail.webp" alt="Black and white photograph presenting the building from a distance on a summer day." width="720" height="576"></a>
<figcaption>Albrecht Hall contained several classrooms, a lovely chapel, and was also used for administrative purposes. Image © Concordia University Wisconsin</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/09-museum.jpg" data-size="1862x1500"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/09-museum-thumbnail.webp" alt="Small museum room containing many taxidermy birds." width="720" height="580"></a>
<figcaption>It also housed a small museum. Image © Concordia University Wisconsin</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/08-mural-2.jpg" data-size="1891x1474"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/08-mural-2-thumbnail.webp" alt="Mural painted on the wall of a conference room. The mural contains some trees along with two old castles behind them. ￼ In 1881 Concordia College held their first class in the basement of Trinity Lutheran Church at 9th and Highland Avenue in downtown Milwaukee. Image © Colin White ￼ The following year they moved west to their new campus. As shown in the 1890 Baist's Property Atlas, the campus borders were North 31st Street, North 33rd Street, West State Street and West Wells Street. It appears that at the time the Milwaukee &amp; Watertown Plank Road still ran along the northern edge of campus. Image © Milwaukee County Land Information Office ￼ A non-distorted view of the campus buildings courtesy of the 1894 Sanborn Fire Insurance Map. Image © Milwaukee County Land Information Office ￼ The 1910 Sanborn Map presents more development in the area as the plank road was removed and more homes were built. Image © Milwaukee County Land Information Office ￼ The Concordia College campus (highlighted in blue) is 5 blocks east of the Miller Brewery and 13 blocks west of Marquette University's western edge. Image © Colin White; © Concordia University Wisconsin; © Molson Coors; © Marquette University ￼ Emil Hamman was the chair and professor of mathematics and science at the college. He served as interim president from 1882-1885. Image © Concordia University Wisconsin ￼ Chr. Loeber, the son of a Concordia founder named Henry Loeber, served as president from 1885-1893. Recent students will recognize this name from Loeber Hall at Concordia University Wisconsin's campus in Mequon. Image © Concordia University Wisconsin ￼ In 1990, seven years after Concordia College left for Mequon, the Forest County Potawatomi Community purchased the land after which they leased it to the Indian Community School. After the school relocated to Franklin in 2007, the Potawatomi evaluated the building conditions and created a long term restoration plan for the newly renamed Wgema Campus. All of the buildings were considered to be in poor shape and required extensive renovations. Image © Colin White ￼ Concordia College president Max Albrecht served from 1893-1921. Afterwards he continued on as a professor of Latin and Greek studies until 1932. Image © Concordia University Wisconsin ￼ Recitation Hall was built in 1900 using a design by architect Eugene Liebert. Eventually the building was renamed in honor of the longtime president and professor as Albrecht Hall. Image © Concordia University Wisconsin ￼ During the warm season of the year, the Kilbourn entrance to Albrecht Hall had a flower bed in front that spell out " width="720" height="561"></a>
<figcaption>As Concordia is a Lutheran institution, some walls were painted with murals of east Germany's Lutherland area; where Martin Luther lived and challenged Roman Catholic doctrine 500 years ago. Image © Concordia University Wisconsin</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/07.3-Albrecht-Hall.jpg" data-size="4027x2736"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/07.3-Albrecht-Hall-thumbnail.webp" alt="The building as it looks today. Very similar in appearance with a field in front." width="720" height="489"></a>
<figcaption>An $11.5 million dollar restoration project was performed on the Wgechda Building which today is home to a tribal court and a community gathering room where the chapel formerly was. "Concordia College" is still prominently engraved along the top of the building. Image © Colin White</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/08.1-refectory-building.jpg" data-size="2387x1500"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/08.1-refectory-building-thumbnail.webp" alt="Two story brick building with a large smoke stack towards the back." width="720" height="452"></a>
<figcaption>Built in 1925, the refectory, or cafeteria, was designed by R.A. Messmer. The second floor contained the campus infirmary and the building housed a power plant towards the back. Image © Concordia University Wisconsin</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/08.2.jpg" data-size="2054x1500"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/08.2-thumbnail.webp" alt="Black and white photo of a cafeteria where many young men are praying before their meal." width="720" height="526"></a>
<figcaption>Meals at the college were served by freshman whom waited on the other students before eating whatever food remained. Image © Concordia University Wisconsin</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/08.3.jpg" data-size="4032x2737"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/08.3-thumbnail.webp" alt="Straight on picture of the front of the 2 story brick building with " width="720" height="489"></a>
<figcaption>Now named Wgemas, it received a $6.5 million renovation to upgrade the space for a senior meal program as well as a cultural center. Image © Colin White</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/09.1-gym-2.jpg" data-size="2304x1500"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/09.1-gym-2-thumbnail.webp" alt="2.5 story brick gymnasium; shaded by trees on a sunny day. Picture is taken from an angle." width="720" height="469"></a>
<figcaption>The R.A. Messmer designed gymnasium was completed in 1930 after the original gymnasium was destroyed by fire in 1927. The gym was the Bucks' practice facility during their early years while a young Lou Alcindor (Kareem Abdul Jabaar) was with the team. Image © Concordia University Wisconsin</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/10-graduation.jpg" data-size="2130x1500"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/10-graduation-thumbnail.webp" alt="A graduation ceremony within the gym building." width="720" height="507"></a>
<figcaption>The gymnasium served as the Concordia College graduation venue. Image © Concordia University Wisconsin</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/09.2._v1.jpg" data-size="2814x1500"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/09.2._v1-thumbnail.webp" alt="Same building today looking straight on. A parking lot is visible in front." width="720" height="384"></a>
<figcaption>The Woodlands School located nearby uses the Tthigwe Building for recess during the day; at night a community basketball program uses it. The Potawatomi plan to begin a nearly $5 million renovation of the 90 year old building sometime in the coming year. Image © Colin White</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/09.4.jpg" data-size="3817x2706"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/09.4-thumbnail.webp" alt="The gymnasium from the side; exposes a more red-toned brick on the expanded portion on the right." width="720" height="510"></a>
<figcaption>Part of the renovation includes the possible demolition of the 1955 swimming pool addition located on the right side of the building. The college used sealants on the addition years ago which exaserbated the moisture control issues; Wisconsin's freeze-thaw cycle lead to shaled brick and degredations elsewhere in the building. Image © Colin White</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/09.3.jpg" data-size="2143x1500"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/09.3-thumbnail.webp" alt="Black and white photo of multiple people relaxing in or on the side of an indoor swimming pool." width="720" height="504"></a>
<figcaption>People enjoying a swim at Concordia College's Ackmann swimming pool. Image © Concordia University Wisconsin</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/11.0-2.jpg" data-size="1255x1500"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/11.0-2-thumbnail.webp" alt="2 story brick college building with 4 limestone columns protruding from the building's face. Entrance is at the top of  stone stairs." width="720" height="861"></a>
<figcaption>In 1941 the E.A. Stubenrauch designed Rincker Library was erected. Image © Concordia University Wisconsin</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/11.1-2.jpg" data-size="1921x1500"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/11.1-2-thumbnail.webp" alt="Tables at the front with students studying. In the rear are two floors of bookcases." width="720" height="562"></a>
<figcaption>According to former student Pastor Wayne Braun, the library had issues meeting accreditation requirements prior to Concordia's exit from Milwaukee. Image © Concordia University Wisconsin</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/11.2-2.jpg" data-size="1901x1500"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/11.2-2-thumbnail.webp" alt="Facing the front windows there are several comfortable chairs with students reading in them. Behind them are the study tables." width="720" height="568"></a>
<figcaption>Image © Concordia University Wisconsin</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/11.3.jpg" data-size="3956x2440"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/11.3-thumbnail.webp" alt="Front of the library from an angle presenting the one floor glass connector to a neighboring building." width="720" height="444"></a>
<figcaption>Rincker Library and Albrecht Hall are now consolidated into a single building named Wgechda. The $3.6 million library building rehabilitation project finished in 2014; it replaced the original, oddly designed building connection with a glass structure. The former library is referred to as Wgechda West while Albrecht Hall is now Wgechda East. Image © Colin White</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/10.0.jpg" data-size="1886x1500"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/10.0-thumbnail.webp" alt="Black and white photo of a 3 story brick building with 50's style cars parked alongside." width="720" height="573"></a>
<figcaption>This 1925 cream city brick building was formerly known as Kilbourn Hall according to CUW's archive. It was used for student housing and "it housed the science laboratory and classroom, the Students' Library and the Sihler Library." Image © Concordia University Wisconsin</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/10.1.jpg" data-size="4019x2346"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/10.1-thumbnail.webp" alt="Front of the cream city brick building." width="720" height="420"></a>
<figcaption>Today the Kilbourn Knoll Apartments contains 12 residences. Image © Colin White</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/12.0.jpg" data-size="1907x1500"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/12.0-thumbnail.webp" alt="Black and white photo of a 3.5 story brick building under construction. An old 20's style car is parked out front with a motorcyle behind it." width="720" height="566"></a>
<figcaption>The R.A. Messmer designed Wunder Dormitory was completed in 1925. To the left of the entrance was a small chapel for students to pray within; to the right of the entrance was the Dean of Women's office. Above the entrance was the resident assitant's room. Image © Concordia University Wisconsin</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/12.1.jpg" data-size="1920x1490"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/12.1-thumbnail.webp" alt="Group of young men reading and studying in a small room." width="720" height="559"></a>
<figcaption>A shared living room in the dormitory circa 1955. Image © Concordia University Wisconsin</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/12.2.jpg" data-size="1888x1500"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/12.2-thumbnail.webp" alt="Group of young men sitting around a radio and relaxing." width="720" height="572"></a>
<figcaption>In another living room the boys listen to the radio. Image © Concordia University Wisconsin</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/12.3.jpg" data-size="4031x2235"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/12.3-thumbnail.webp" alt="A picture of the front of the former Wunder Dormitory. Two leave less trees are in front of the building." width="720" height="399"></a>
<figcaption>After the conlusion of a 2012 $5 million renovation, Wunder Dormitory was renamed Bgemagen which translates to War Club. The building is office space for several businesses including the Potawatomi owned Potawatomi Business Development Corporation and construction firm Greenfire Management Services. According to their website, Potawatomi BDC is "the economic development and income diversification business of the Forest County Potawatomi Community." Greenfire has constructed buildings all over Wisconsin including the $100 million in-progress construction of Michels headquarters in Milwaukee's Harbor District. Image © Colin White</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/13-moving_v2-2.jpg" data-size="2090x1500"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/13-moving_v2-2-thumbnail.webp" alt="4 men in a black and white photo carrying boxes on the campus." width="720" height="517"></a>
<figcaption>This 1959 picture shows former Concordia president Walter W. Stuenkel's son Robert moving into the dorms. Image © Concordia University Wisconsin</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/coeducation.jpg" data-size="1848x1500"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/coeducation-thumbnail.webp" alt="Newspaper clipping from 1965 with the headline " width="720" height="584"></a>
<figcaption>Concordia College was for men only until the 1965 school year. Wunder Dormitory transitioned to female dormitories while male students moved into the new constructed Pritzlaff Dormitory across the way. A former student said the women were playfully referred to as "Wunder women." Image © Concordia University Wisconsin</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/14-moving2-2.jpg" data-size="1610x1500"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/14-moving2-2-thumbnail.webp" alt="A man exiting a building with arms full of boxes and various other items." width="720" height="671"></a>
<figcaption>Image © Concordia University Wisconsin</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/13.0.jpg" data-size="2292x1500"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/13.0-thumbnail.webp" alt="A 3 story L shaped brick building on a sunny summer day." width="720" height="471"></a>
<figcaption>According to Concordia University, the L shaped Pritzlaff Dormitory was constructed as three wings. Section A, which runs along State Street, was completed in 1950 while the other two sections that run along N 31st St were completed by 1954. The building was designed by Sheboygan architect Edgar A. Stubenrauch. Section A was eventually converted into office space after being vacant for several years due to declining enrollment. Image © Concordia University Wisconsin</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/14-studentLounge.jpg" data-size="1903x1500"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/14-studentLounge-thumbnail.webp" alt="Small student lounge containing a few tables and a store counter in back." width="720" height="568"></a>
<figcaption>Located on the first floor of Pritzlaff, the student lounge in 1955 was pretty humble. Image © Concordia University Wisconsin</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/14-studentLounge2.jpg" data-size="1857x1500"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/14-studentLounge2-thumbnail.webp" alt="An upgraded, 1960's style, student lounge." width="720" height="582"></a>
<figcaption>The lounge received a contemporary makeover in 1965. Image © Concordia University Wisconsin</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/13.1.jpg" data-size="4032x3024"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/13.1-thumbnail.webp" alt="The 3 story L shaped brick building on a sunny winter day." width="720" height="540"></a>
<figcaption>Pritzlaff Dormitory was renovated for $1.6 million and renamed Nengos in 2014. The Indian Community School occupied it from 1990 through 2007 at which time they moved into their new school building in Franklin. Current tenant the Woodlands School opened their second campus here in 2013. Image © Colin White</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/13.2.jpg" data-size="4032x3024"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/13.2-thumbnail.webp" alt="A portion of the 3 story brick building." width="720" height="540"></a>
<figcaption>The State Street side of Nengos, where section A and B connects, has a service door visible at the bottom left of the photograph; this was the site of the Concordia campus bookstore. Image © Colin White</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/14-2.jpg" data-size="4032x3024"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/14-2-thumbnail.webp" alt="A large playground in front of Nengos on the right and Bgemagen on the left." width="720" height="540"></a>
<figcaption>The Woodlands School playground was an open space during Concordia's years. Students had nicknamed the area "Fort Blitz" as they would stand atop the dormitory buildings and throw snowballs at unfortunate people that happened to wander by. Image © Colin White</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/15-wunderPritz.jpg" data-size="2291x1500"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/15-wunderPritz-thumbnail.webp" alt="A view east at Wunder Dormitory and Pritzlaff Dormitory in the 1960's." width="720" height="471"></a>
<figcaption>Image © Concordia University Wisconsin</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/15.0.png" data-size="1380x976"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/15.0-thumbnail.webp" alt="2 story brick college building with a large green space in front. A small stone retaining wall is in the forefront." width="720" height="509"></a>
<figcaption>The State Street Building was Concordia College's final construction project. It was located on the north side of State Street and contained several classrooms. It was later home to Spotted Eagle High School before being demolished in 2012 to make way for a data center. Image © Concordia University Wisconsin</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/16-in-class.jpg" data-size="2230x1500"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/16-in-class-thumbnail.webp" alt="Mostly female students receiving a lecture from a man at a lectern at the front of the classroom." width="720" height="484"></a>
<figcaption>Image © Concordia University Wisconsin</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/01-gisAerial.jpg" data-size="1629x1500"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/01-gisAerial-thumbnail.webp" alt="An aerial view of the Concordia campus showing the space between West State Street and West Highland Boulevard. There is a baseball diamond situated here." width="720" height="663"></a>
<figcaption>Concordia College had a baseball diamond to the west of the former State Street Building. Image © Milwaukee County Land Information Office</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/02-team1925.jpg" data-size="1997x1500"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/02-team1925-thumbnail.webp" alt="Group photo of the baseball team." width="720" height="541"></a>
<figcaption>The Concordia baseball team in 1925. Image © Concordia University Wisconsin</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/02-team1930.jpg" data-size="2223x1500"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/02-team1930-thumbnail.webp" alt="Group photo of the baseball team outside standing in front of some campus buildings." width="720" height="486"></a>
<figcaption>The Concordia baseball team in 1930. Image © Concordia University Wisconsin</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/15.1.jpg" data-size="3807x2191"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/15.1-thumbnail.webp" alt="A new tall two story brick building with a large black fence protecting in front." width="720" height="414"></a>
<figcaption>After the State Street Building demolition, the Leroy Shockto Sr. Building was completed in 2013 to house a data center operated by Data Holdings. The Wgema Campus Police Department headquarters is also located within. The surrounding area has seen a 10-15% decrease in crime during recent years. Image © Colin White</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/18.4.jpg" data-size="4032x3024"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/18.4-thumbnail.webp" alt="An array of solar panels on a grass lot with a surrounding fence." width="720" height="540"></a>
<figcaption>A solar panel array was installed directly west of the Leroy Shockto Sr. Building early in 2020 on the former baseball field. Image © Colin White</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/16.0.jpg" data-size="1452x1500"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/16.0-thumbnail.webp" alt="Black and white photograph of a two story house with a five story tower within." width="720" height="744"></a>
<figcaption>The Concordia neighborhood is home to many historic homes and buildings such as the 1851 Faries-Rood-Yale Tower House located at at 3011 W. State St. Concordia College purchased the Tower House in 1960 and used it as an admissions office through the 1970's. Image © Concordia University Wisconsin</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/16.1.jpg" data-size="2986x3278"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/16.1-thumbnail.webp" alt="The cream city brick tower house today after a restoration." width="720" height="790"></a>
<figcaption>The home received a thorough renovation recently and is now a private residence. Image © Colin White</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/17.0.jpg" data-size="1891x1500"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/17.0-thumbnail.webp" alt="Old photo of an ornate, single story house with two stone lion statues on either side of the entrance." width="720" height="571"></a>
<figcaption>The Edward V. Koch designed Lion House is another iconic neighborhood building constructed in 1897. It housed the Concordia College development office for a short period. Image © Concordia University Wisconsin</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/17.1.jpg" data-size="3276x2796"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/17.1-thumbnail.webp" alt="Current photo of an ornate, single story, cream city brick house with two stone lion statues on either side of the entrance." width="720" height="615"></a>
<figcaption>Today it is owned by the Forest County Potawatomi and leased out as office space. Image © Colin White</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/18.0.jpg" data-size="1925x1500"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/18.0-thumbnail.webp" alt="Black and white photo of a block of 2.5 story houses with cars parked in front." width="720" height="561"></a>
<figcaption>Concordia College owned a large number of residences in the surrounding area. They allowed faculty or married students to live in some while others were rented out while the college worked on plans to expand the campus. One block along W. Kilbourn Ave. was dubbed "Faculty Row" since some professors and their families lived there. Image © Concordia University Wisconsin</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/18.1.jpg" data-size="1623x1492"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/18.1-thumbnail.webp" alt="An aerial view of the Concordia campus showing a new track at the center." width="720" height="662"></a>
<figcaption>Faculty Row was demolished in the 1970's to make way for a running track south of the gymnasium. Image © Milwaukee County Land Information Office</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/18.2.jpg" data-size="3410x1541"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/18.2-thumbnail.webp" alt="A parking lot with several buildings in the distance." width="720" height="325"></a>
<figcaption>Between 2014 and 2019 the track was removed and replaced with a new Wgema Campus parking lot and structure. Image © Colin White</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/18.3.jpg" data-size="4022x2235"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/18.3-thumbnail.webp" alt="Open grass field on a sunny winter day." width="720" height="400"></a>
<figcaption>The Potawatomi Community submitted a proposal in November of 2020 to install more than 800 solar panels capable of generating 335 kilowatts of energy in an empty grass parcel. These solar panels would be located south of the Tigawa gymnasium where Faculty Row used to be. It is zoned for $250 thousand of light industrial so it may one day house another data center. Image © Colin White</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/01-campus-bus.jpg" data-size="2689x1500"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/01-campus-bus-thumbnail.webp" alt="A man leaning on a 1940's style bus branded with " width="720" height="402"></a>
<figcaption>After Concordia College demolished several blocks of old houses, many neighborhood residents became unnerved. The college did a poor job of managing their rental properties; likely owed to their plan to demolish them and expand the campus. Community members feared the history and character of their neighborhood would be irrevocably changed by the continued demolition of old houses.</figcaption>
</figure>
<figure class="gallery__item"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/02.jpg" data-size="2090x1500"><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/14/gallery/02-thumbnail.webp" alt="An aerial view of the Concordia campus in Mequon from the 1980's." width="720" height="517"></a>
<figcaption>After struggling for years to convince neighbors or city officials of their need to expand, in 1983 Concordia College finally decided to purchase the 102 acre School Sisters of Notre Dame campus in Mequon for $7.1 million. The student population grew from around 300 in 1983 to more than 7 thousand today. Image © Concordia University Wisconsin</figcaption>
</figure>
</div></div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Wgema Campus Development Continues</title>
        <author>
            <name>Colin White</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/wgema-campus-development-continues.html"/>
        <id>https://MkeCountyBlog.com/wgema-campus-development-continues.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/15/gym.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Wgema Campus"/>
            <category term="Potawatomi"/>
            <category term="Concordia College"/>
            <category term="CUW"/>

        <updated>2020-12-24T15:13:37-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/15/gym.jpg" alt="Two story brick gymnasium with &quot;Concordia College Gymnasium&quot; in limestone above the door." />
                    On Friday the director of facilities for Potawatomi Business Development Corporation Joe Tesch discussed future construction plans for Potawatomi’s Wgema&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/15/gym.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Two story brick gymnasium with &quot;Concordia College Gymnasium&quot; in limestone above the door." /></p>
                <p>On Friday the director of facilities for Potawatomi Business Development Corporation Joe Tesch discussed future construction plans for Potawatomi’s Wgema Campus located in Milwaukee’s historic Concordia neighborhood.</p>
<p>In November they submitted a proposal to install more than 800 solar panels capable of generating 335 kilowatts of energy in an empty grass parcel across from the Tthigwe gymnasium building. The site is zoned for $250 thousand of light industrial but the campus is located within the Concordia Historic District and needs approval from the Milwaukee Historic Preservation Commission before they may proceed.</p>
<p>“We need to keep the solar array there for 5 years to satisfy the grant. I would say after five years there could be another data center or you know some kind of light industrial building built,” said Tesch.</p>
<p>This would be the second array of solar panels installed at the campus. Earlier this year the first array was activated west of the LEED Gold certified Leroy Shockto Sr. Building at 3135 W. Highland Blvd. The Wgema campus is the largest LEED certified site in Milwaukee. LEED, or Leadership in Energy and Environmental Design, is an international green building certification program.</p>
<p>Linda Hanig, a 44 year nearby resident said “Personally I think it’s really nice that they’re going to be very environmentally conscious that way.”</p>
<p>The Tthigwe building’s 1955 swimming pool addition was scheduled to be demolished this past March. The project is currently being reevaluated so the structure may be renovated instead. Originally built for Concordia College, the pool building is part of a $4.5 million gymnasium renovation plan.</p>
<p>Tesch said, “The brick that is shaling off; so it’s the freeze-thaw thing that happens here in Wisconsin. Yeah back in the day they tried to protect the parapet from all the moisture and they just made it worse.”</p>
<p>Concordia College, known today as Concordia University Wisconsin, built the campus in 1881 before moving to Mequon in 1983. The Potawatomi purchased the site in 1990 and started planning renovations for the newly named campus in 2007.</p>
<hr>
<p><strong>Sources</strong></p>
<ol class="ordered-list">
<li>
<p>Joe Tesch - Director of Facilities at Potawatomi Business Development Corporation</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Linda Hanig – Longtime local resident</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Solar Panel Information</p>
<p><a href="https://www.jsonline.com/story/money/business/energy/2020/11/24/potawatomi-wants-install-848-solar-panels-milwaukees-west-side/6408287002/">https://www.jsonline.com/story/money/business/energy/2020/11/24/potawatomi-wants-install-848-solar-panels-milwaukees-west-side/6408287002/</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Swimming Pool Annexation Year</p>
<p><a href="https://cdm15983.contentdm.oclc.org/digital/collection/history/id/56/rec/1">https://cdm15983.contentdm.oclc.org/digital/collection/history/id/56/rec/1</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Concordia College historic information</p>
<p><a href="https://www.cuw.edu/about/history.html">https://www.cuw.edu/about/history.html</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Concordia feels the city’s tug in its serene retreat</p>
<p>The Milwaukee Journal – January 12, 1989 Page 89</p>
</li>
</ol>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Looking Back At Concordia College</title>
        <author>
            <name>Colin White</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/looking-back-at-concordia-college.html"/>
        <id>https://MkeCountyBlog.com/looking-back-at-concordia-college.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/16/08.1-refectory-building.jpeg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Wgema Campus"/>
            <category term="Potawatomi"/>
            <category term="Concordia College"/>
            <category term="CUW"/>

        <updated>2020-12-24T22:52:21-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/16/08.1-refectory-building.jpeg" alt="Two story brick refectory from an angle. A large smoke stack is visible on the roof. &quot;Concordia College&quot; in metal letters over the side entrance." />
                    A short audio story exploring life on campus and why the college moved to Mequon. It features former Concordia College&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/16/08.1-refectory-building.jpeg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Two story brick refectory from an angle. A large smoke stack is visible on the roof. &quot;Concordia College&quot; in metal letters over the side entrance." /></p>
                <p>A short audio story exploring life on campus and why the college moved to Mequon. It features former Concordia College student Wayne Braun; presently the senior pastor at Fishers of Men Lutheran Church in Texas.  He and his wife were members of the first class to receive a four year bachelor of arts degree from the college in 1980.</p>
<p><audio loading="lazy" controls="controls">
  <source src="https://mkecountyblog.com/CC_LookBack.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" />
Your browser does not support the audio element.</audio></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Concordia to Wgema: 40 Years of Transitions</title>
        <author>
            <name>Colin White</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/concordia-to-wgema-40-years-of-transitions.html"/>
        <id>https://MkeCountyBlog.com/concordia-to-wgema-40-years-of-transitions.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/17/2006.jpeg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Wgema Campus"/>
            <category term="Concordia College"/>

        <updated>2021-05-26T14:14:51-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/17/2006.jpeg" alt="Old 3.5 story brick college building with leave-less trees flanking it in front." />
                    The Concordia neighborhood in Milwaukee's West End was named after Concordia College which was located there from 1881 until they&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/17/2006.jpeg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Old 3.5 story brick college building with leave-less trees flanking it in front." /></p>
                <p>The Concordia neighborhood in Milwaukee's West End was named after Concordia College which was located there from 1881 until they relocated to Mequon in 1983. The campus and many surrounding residences were sold to the Forest County Potawatomi in 1990. The following stories provide an overview of how the campus has changed over time.</p>
<h3 class="align-center"><figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/17/thenAndNow.jpeg" alt="" width="254" height="200" sizes="100vw" srcset="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/17/responsive/thenAndNow-xs.webp 300w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/17/responsive/thenAndNow-sm.webp 480w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/17/responsive/thenAndNow-md.webp 768w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/17/responsive/thenAndNow-lg.webp 1024w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/17/responsive/thenAndNow-xl.webp 1360w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/17/responsive/thenAndNow-2xl.webp 1600w"></figure></h3>
<h3 class="align-center"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/campus-buildings-then-and-now.html">Campus Buildings Then &amp; Now </a></h3>
<h3 class="align-center"> </h3>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/17/aLookBack.jpeg" alt="" width="318" height="200" sizes="100vw" srcset="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/17/responsive/aLookBack-xs.webp 300w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/17/responsive/aLookBack-sm.webp 480w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/17/responsive/aLookBack-md.webp 768w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/17/responsive/aLookBack-lg.webp 1024w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/17/responsive/aLookBack-xl.webp 1360w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/17/responsive/aLookBack-2xl.webp 1600w"></figure>
<h3 class="align-center"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/looking-back-at-concordia-college.html">Looking Back At Concordia College in Milwaukee</a></h3>
<p> </p>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/17/transformationContinues.jpeg" alt="" width="375" height="200" sizes="100vw" srcset="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/17/responsive/transformationContinues-xs.webp 300w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/17/responsive/transformationContinues-sm.webp 480w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/17/responsive/transformationContinues-md.webp 768w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/17/responsive/transformationContinues-lg.webp 1024w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/17/responsive/transformationContinues-xl.webp 1360w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/17/responsive/transformationContinues-2xl.webp 1600w"></figure>
<h3 class="align-center"><a href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/wgema-campus-development-continues.html">Wgema Campus Development Continues</a></h3>
<p> </p>
<p class="align-center"><div class="post__iframe"><iframe loading="lazy" width="425" height="350" style="border: 1px solid black;" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" src="https://www.openstreetmap.org/export/embed.html?bbox=-87.96079487721005%2C43.03848536272863%2C-87.94643969456234%2C43.045173931869&amp;layer=mapnik"></iframe></div><small><a href="https://www.openstreetmap.org/#map=17/43.04183/-87.95362"></a></small></p>
<p class="align-center"><small><a href="https://www.openstreetmap.org/#map=17/43.04183/-87.95362">View Larger Map</a></small></p>
<h3 class="align-center">Concordia/Wgema Campus Additional Reading</h3>
<ul>
<li>Potawatomi BDC - <a href="https://www.potawatomibdc.com/s/Wgema-Campus-small-file.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wgema Campus Pictoral Timeline</a></li>
<li>OnMilwaukee Urban Spelunking - <a href="https://onmilwaukee.com/on/Concordia%20College" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Concordia College</a></li>
<li>OnMilwaukee Urban Spelunking - <a href="https://onmilwaukee.com/articles/fariesroodspelunking" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Tower House</a></li>
<li>Encyclopedia of Milwaukee - <a href="https://emke.uwm.edu/entry/concordia/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Concordia</a></li>
<li>Encyclopedia of Milwaukee - <a href="https://emke.uwm.edu/entry/indian-community-school/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Indian Community School</a></li>
<li>Wisconsin Historical Society - <a href="https://www.wisconsinhistory.org/Records?&amp;terms=concordia%2ccollege&amp;facets=Community%3a%22Milwaukee%22%2cCONTENT_TYPE%3a%22Property+Record%22" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Individual Concordia College Building Histories</a></li>
</ul>
<p>My warm thanks to the Potawatomi employees and the many neighborhood residents that gave their time to help me form a better understanding of the Concordia neighborhood as it existed in the 1970's through today.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Securing the Final Link in the Absentee Ballot Chain</title>
        <author>
            <name>Colin White</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/securing-the-final-link-in-the-absentee-ballot-chain.html"/>
        <id>https://MkeCountyBlog.com/securing-the-final-link-in-the-absentee-ballot-chain.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/9/joshua-woroniecki-nSbsfmvURt8-unsplash.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Wisconsin"/>
            <category term="Security"/>
            <category term="Election"/>
            <category term="Absentee Ballot"/>

        <updated>2020-11-15T08:03:25-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/9/joshua-woroniecki-nSbsfmvURt8-unsplash.jpg" alt="The stars from the American flag with a card laying on top of the stripes that says &quot;BALLOT ENCLOSED&quot; " />
                    With election 2020 winding down (hopefully🤞) we once again have claims of election fraud flying around; this time in regards&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/9/joshua-woroniecki-nSbsfmvURt8-unsplash.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="The stars from the American flag with a card laying on top of the stripes that says &quot;BALLOT ENCLOSED&quot; " /></p>
                
  <p>
    With election 2020 winding down (hopefully🤞) we once again have claims of election fraud flying around; this time in regards to absentee (mail-in) ballots. Putting the actual prevalence of absentee voting fraud aside; let's look at where some realistic vulnerabilities in the current process are and one idea on how to deal with them. Absentee voting is handled pretty well in Wisconsin with a few areas left to improve upon. Below is a summary of my understanding of the current voting process.
  </p>

  <ol>
    <li><a href="https://myvote.wi.gov/en-US/RegisterToVote" target="_blank">Register to vote</a>: requires <a href="https://elections.wi.gov/publications/voter-guides/proof-of-residence" target="_blank">proof of residence</a> (Driver’s License or state ID works here)</li><li>Signup for an absentee ballot (aka mail-in ballot.)</li><li>Receive ballot in the mail.</li><li>Find a witness.</li><li>Fill out your ballot.</li><li>Place completed ballot in the included envelope and seal it.</li><li>Fill out your address and sign the exterior of the envelope.</li><li>Have a witness fill out their address and then sign the envelope.</li><li>Put your ballot in a mailbox for USPS pickup 📬.</li><li>USPS picks up the ballot and takes it to a sorting facility 📪.</li><li>The ballot is delivered to your local polling place.</li><li>On election day information from #7 and #8 is verified; the envelope is opened; your ballot is sent through the voting machine; vote is cast; process done.<br></li>
  </ol>

  <p>
    The link in the chain that remains particularly contentious and open to <a href="https://www.msn.com/en-us/news/politics/philadelphia-election-judge-admits-to-stuffing-ballot-boxes-for-democrats-in-three-separate-elections/ar-BB14qWhl" target="_blank">legitimate fraud</a>&nbsp;is step #12. If a voter fills out an absentee ballot they are likely not at the polling place when their ballot is removed and put through the voting machine. Our current system relies on voters to trust their local polling place volunteers to honestly cast their absentee votes; many believe this is an opening for cheating. Below is one idea how to address this concern and help voters verify that their ballots weren’t manipulated before being run through the voting machine.
  </p>

  <ol>
    <li>Fill out your ballot</li><li>Go to the state voting website and open the (new!) ballot validation page.</li><li>Fill out required information including your name and address as well as voting selections.</li><li>The website will use this information to create a unique confirmation code without the information ever leaving your computer.</li><li>Write down the code and then mail your ballot.</li><li>After the ballot is cast, the voting website will present a confirmation code generated as the vote is processed at the polling location using the same information on the actual ballot that was used during step #4.</li><li>If the codes from #4 and #6 match, no tampering took place; if they don’t something went wrong and you contact the state election’s board.</li>
  </ol>

  <p>
    The above process should be optional but would allow anyone to verify for themselves that their ballot contained their unaltered selections. Trust shifts from the volunteers to the voting machines that process ballots. Any change to the ballot would generate a different confirmation code thus informing the voter that something went wrong with their ballot. In that event they can contact the local authorities or the election board.
  </p>

  <p>
    The rest of the voting process can use some improvements as well. I consider the witness requirement in Wisconsin to be an unnecessary burden and an example of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Security_theater" target="_blank">security theater</a>. According to the <i><a href="https://www.chicagotribune.com/election-2020/ct-nw-2020-ballot-witness-notary-public-requirement-20200925-sg4n6sf6prd5hetrzl6iqml25a-story.html" target="_blank">Associated Press</a></i>,
  </p>

    <figure class="blockquote">
      <blockquote>Proponents of the requirement say it’s designed to prevent voter fraud by holding others accountable for vouching for a voter.</blockquote>
      <figcaption>AP: Gary D. Robertson & Scott Bauer</figcaption>
    </figure>

  <p>
    It is difficult to fathom the type of crime this is preventing. This appears more likely to cause a valid ballot to be tossed than to prevent any real election malfeasance. If a person is willing to falsify ballots or manipulate votes in some way why would they then have any issue with falsifying the witness portion of the ballot? If you have an idea please let me know in the comments.
  </p>

  <p>
    Finally, verifying that a person is a resident of the state before they vote is an important part of any election and I believe the voter ID requirement is a logical way to do so. Those without a driver’s license are able to get a free photo ID card from the DMV. Planning ahead and taking some time to go get an ID seems like a reasonable requirement that allows more people to trust the voting process.
  </p>

  <p>
    Many will argue that voter fraud is rare; however many others seem to believe it is prevalent and tipping the scales in their opponent's favor. This fairly simple, free ID requirement seems to address some of the second group's concerns. My proposed idea may enable the remainder of the absentee voting process to become more trustworthy as well. The goal for Wisconsin as well as the rest of the United States should be to maintain the credibility of our elections and continually evaluate options for doing so.
  </p>

  <p>
    <b>Update 11/15/20</b><br>After more consideration as well as observing some of the shenanigans happening around the country, the confirmation code idea is open to misuse. Nothing prevents a person from generating multiple confirmations and then claiming ballot manipulation after the fact. Oh well, back to the drawing board.<br>
  </p>

  <p>
    Featured image by <a href="https://unsplash.com/@joshua_j_woroniecki?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText">Joshua Woroniecki</a> on <a href="https://unsplash.com/s/photos/election?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText">Unsplash</a>.
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Resolution For ProtonMail Bridge &amp; Thunderbird SMTP Issue</title>
        <author>
            <name>Colin White</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/protonmail-bridge-and-thunderbird-smtp-issue-resolution.html"/>
        <id>https://MkeCountyBlog.com/protonmail-bridge-and-thunderbird-smtp-issue-resolution.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/8/fongit-2.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Thunderbird"/>
            <category term="ProtonMail"/>
            <category term="Privacy"/>
            <category term="Open Source"/>
            <category term="Email"/>

        <updated>2020-10-12T10:54:44-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/8/fongit-2.jpg" alt="Picture of ProtonMail&#x27;s 5 story teal office building in Geneva." />
                    While setting up the ProtonMail Bridge with Thunderbird 78.3.2 today I discovered that Thunderbird's standard self-signed certificate dialog no longer&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/8/fongit-2.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Picture of ProtonMail&#x27;s 5 story teal office building in Geneva." /></p>
                <p>While setting up the ProtonMail Bridge with Thunderbird 78.3.2 today I discovered that Thunderbird's standard self-signed certificate dialog no longer appears before sending the first message; making sending emails impossible. While ducking around (<a href="https://duckduckgo.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">duckduckgo.com</a>) I discovered this is a known bug that will be fixed in an upcoming release of Thunderbird; but I want to use it now!!! 🙎🤣</p>
<p>My work around is tedious but simple.</p>
<ol>
<li>Open ProtonMail Bridge.</li>
<li>Click the 'Settings' button.</li>
<li>'Advanced Settings.'</li>
<li>'Change IMAP &amp; SMTP settings.'</li>
<li>Change the IMAP &amp; SMTP ports to a random number like 1145 and 1026 respectively and then click 'Okay.'</li>
<li>Bridge will automatically close and reopen. Follow steps 2-5 but this time only change the IMAP port to 1025.</li>
<li>Open Thunderbird and setup a new account using account information from Bridge.</li>
<li>Permanently store the certificate when the scary message pops open.</li>
<li>In Thunderbird delete the account from step 7-8.</li>
<li>In Bridge repeat steps 2-5. This time set the default ports again. (IMAP: 1143  SMTP: 1025)</li>
<li>Repeat Steps 7-8 and enjoy!</li>
</ol>
<p>I have been hopping back and forth between <a href="https://mailbox.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">mailbox.org</a> and <a href="https://protonmail.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">ProtonMail</a> for a couple of years. ProtonMail has come along far enough now that I believe I'll stick with them for the long term. My primary reasoning behind paying a premium for their service is my email is all stored encrypted on their servers; in the unlikely event anyone broke into their infrastructure, all the villains would find readable are the recipients and the subject of my emails (neither of which concerns me.) As I occasionally receive tax and other financial information through email, this grants me some peace of mind. With Proton, incoming email is the main vulnerability as this is the only point in the chain where it remains unencrypted in relation to their servers.</p>
<p>I have read others criticize ProtonMail for not supporting IMAP and SMTP standards used by ordinary email providers (gmail, Outlook, Zoho) but I believe this argument is flawed. Other email providers expect users to do all of the work of encrypting emails themselves which a tiny fraction of a percent of users actually do. ProtonMail was developed with the goal of privacy, security and ease of use out of the box which makes using the existing standards too restraining.</p>
<p>Removing the complexity and annoyance of PGP is a relief (I was using it client side for several years prior to the switch to ProtonMail.) Attempting to manually encrypt all of my existing unencrypted emails was a nightmare that Proton greatly simplified.</p>
<p>One final point is that ProtonMail allows IMAP and SMTP access on the desktop through their bridge application. While it is certainly slower than an unencrypted alternative, I find the lag to be within an acceptable amount. I am also happy they <a href="https://github.com/ProtonMail" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">have open sourced</a> the majority of their client code as of October 2020.</p>
<p>There is still more work to do on their end to polish and improve but as of now, they are much closer to having a PGP email product I can recommend to my folks without having to worry about constant problems. I cannot say the same for IMAP SMTP clients using PGP.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Wisconsin Governor&#x27;s Vetoes Tip The Scales</title>
        <author>
            <name>Colin White</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/wisconsin-governors-vetoes-tip-the-scales.html"/>
        <id>https://MkeCountyBlog.com/wisconsin-governors-vetoes-tip-the-scales.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/7/Wisconsin_Supreme_Court-3.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Wisconsin Supreme Court"/>
            <category term="Wisconsin"/>
            <category term="Governor"/>

        <updated>2020-10-11T15:28:14-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/7/Wisconsin_Supreme_Court-3.jpg" alt="Court room of the Wisconsin Supreme Court in Madison&#x27;s state capitol building." />
                    This post sprang to mind while thinking about the Wisconsin governor's veto powers after a recent Wisconsin Supreme Court ruling&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/7/Wisconsin_Supreme_Court-3.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Court room of the Wisconsin Supreme Court in Madison&#x27;s state capitol building." /></p>
                
  <p>
    This post sprang to mind while thinking about the Wisconsin governor's veto powers after a <a href="https://www.wpr.org/wisconsin-supreme-court-strikes-down-3-evers-vetoes" target="_blank">recent Wisconsin Supreme Court ruling</a> that attempted to clarify restrictions to this broad power amended to our state constitution in 1930. Much of the commentary focused on the specific vetoes from today's case but my thoughts shifted towards why Wisconsin has such a strong veto and why so much power was placed in a single branch of our state government. This year I have been reading&nbsp;<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Conservative-Sensibility-George-F-Will-ebook/dp/B07J525HRP/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">The Conservative Sensibility</a> by George F. Will. The first few chapters discuss the original design of the United States' federal government with a thorough description of the intended limits and separations.
  </p>

  <p>
    The progressive movement gained steam in the early 20th century and progressively (see what I did there&nbsp;😉) tilted the balance of power towards the executive branch and away from the legislative and judicial branches. The design of the Wisconsin veto appeared to follow a similar pattern as described in the book. The veto turned out to be the result of a legitimate concern of how the bundling of many individual issues into a single, massive appropriation bill could force the governor to accept budget items that he disagrees with in order to allow the rest of the bill to pass. This was wonderful foresight as the United States has this very issue in Congress today. It appears hardly anyone in Congress knows the content of the bills they sign or reject as they have become so long and complicated as to make the task of reading them in their entirety nearly impossible prior to voting.
  </p>

    <figure class="blockquote">
      <blockquote>Early critics of the omnibus appropriations process worried that it bundled too many disparate concerns into one bill that a governor would be forced to either sign into law or veto in full. This approach unfairly strengthened the Legislature's power over a governor's, their argument held, by effectively forcing a governor to accept individual budget items that they may not support in order to pass the larger budget bill. This fear heightened in the late 1920s, when a new law required the governor to propose a single budget, effectively ending any possibility that a state budget could be passed piece by piece.<br><br>In an effort to rebalance powers over the state budget, state Senator William Titus, a Progressive from Fond du Lac, proposed a constitutional amendment in 1927 that would give governors the ability to veto pieces of an appropriations bill.</blockquote>
      <figcaption>Will Cushman, WisContext</figcaption>
    </figure>

  <p>
    Unfortunately governors of course eventually abused this veto power. Instead of vetoing specific budget items, governors began removing numbers, letters, and words to change the legislature's intended meaning; a gross misuse of power outside of the governor's purview. A made up example below illustrates how the governor could change a bill that sends a large amount of money to Milwaukee school libraries into a tiny amount of money for public schools.
  </p>

    <blockquote class="blockquote">
      <b>Originally:</b>&nbsp;"$10,000 to Milwaukee Public School Libraries"<br><b>Veto Applied:</b> "$10<s>,000</s> to <s>Milwaukee </s>Public School<s> Librarie</s>s"<br><b>Result:</b> "$10 to Public Schools"<br>
    </blockquote>

  <p>
    Government at most levels appears to have expanded well outside of their intended purposes. The legislature is intended to create and introduce legislation; the governor is intended to approve or veto the legislation they propose. The shift away from these roles has helped provide a significantly less reliable government for us today. For further reading, a very fine history of the Wisconsin veto is available from <a href="https://wiscontext.org/story-wisconsins-singular-partial-veto" target="_blank">WisContext</a>.
  </p>

  <p>
    
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Simplifying Lists/Notes/To-do Organization With CalDAV</title>
        <author>
            <name>Colin White</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/simplifying-listsnotesto-do-organization-with-caldav.html"/>
        <id>https://MkeCountyBlog.com/simplifying-listsnotesto-do-organization-with-caldav.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/6/luis-villasmil-mlVbMbxfWI4-unsplash.jpg" medium="image" />
            <category term="iPhone"/>
            <category term="WebDAV"/>
            <category term="Wallabag"/>
            <category term="Pocket"/>
            <category term="Organization"/>
            <category term="Open Source"/>
            <category term="Nextcloud"/>
            <category term="Linux"/>
            <category term="Joplin"/>
            <category term="CalDAV"/>
            <category term="Apple"/>
            <category term="Android"/>

        <updated>2020-06-13T15:45:31-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/6/luis-villasmil-mlVbMbxfWI4-unsplash.jpg" alt="Man in the corner of a room covered in different post it reminders." />
                    Finding an intuitive way to organize notes and to-dos into a simple, cross-platform tool has been a tiring multiyear search.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/6/luis-villasmil-mlVbMbxfWI4-unsplash.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Man in the corner of a room covered in different post it reminders." /></p>
                
  <p>
    Finding an intuitive way to organize notes and to-dos into a simple, cross-platform tool has been a tiring multiyear search. I started with Pocket for storing articles and Joplin for notes but ended up using Nextcloud's builtin CalDAV as well as the many good clients this provides. Saved articles are primarily used for improving&nbsp;<a href="https://www.openstreetmap.org/#map=15/43.0427/-87.9159" target="_blank" class="">OpenStreetMap</a>&nbsp;in the Milwaukee region. Notes are mostly quick reference points for Linux commands that I don't want to forget (or remember) as well as lists of books/movies/music to consume later or a place to jot down some notes during a meeting.
  </p>

  <p>
    <a href="https://joplinapp.org/" target="_blank">Joplin</a> worked fairly well but only works comfortably within their electron app; limiting client options. Its main selling point compared to other similar products is that it stores all files, optionally encrypted, locally on your device. Syncing is optionally done with services like Nextcloud, Google Drive or Dropbox. During my time with it, they introduced the Web-Clipper enabling users to copy an entire article's content into a note thus making Pocket redundant. Every link stored with Pocket thus was individually opened in order to clip into Joplin before deleting the Pocket account. However, Joplin never worked as quickly or flexibly as I hoped for. To make or check a note requires starting up the Joplin app, waiting for it to load, and entering the password (if encrypted). At the time (2018?), sync issues were common. For what it does Joplin is a great tool but was unable to provide what I needed (web-clipping on mobile.)
  </p>

  <p>
    So I once again began the laborious process of opening links from Joplin to move to a self-hosted <a href="https://www.wallabag.it/en" target="_blank">Wallabag</a> instance. Notes stored in Joplin were converted to text based markdown files for use with Nextcloud Notes. Wallabag provides <i>most</i> of the function and convenience of Pocket without the payment and 3rd party involvement. This was satisfying for a year or two but ran into the similar feeling with Joplin. The workflow never felt very fluid and the actual effort of getting information when needed was tiring. The Android app worked well but the iOS apps I encountered were frustratingly designed resulting in one more laborious shift&nbsp;(I'm sure the last! 😜)  from Wallabag to CalDAV.
  </p>

    <h3 id="at-long-last-a-solution">
      At Long Last: A Solution!
    </h3>

  <p>
    According to&nbsp;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CalDAV" target="_blank">Wikipedia</a>,&nbsp;CalDAV&nbsp;is a WebDAV extension that "allows multiple client access to the same information thus allowing cooperative planning and information sharing." There are many CalDAV providers and clients of all shapes and sizes providing the flexibility I have long desired. In my case I already had a Nextcloud instance setup at home for syncing calendars, contacts and files so an existing CalDAV server was ready to go. CalDAV is builtin to popular Linux desktop environments as well as Apple products; has a great app on Android (<a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=at.bitfire.davdroid&amp;hl=en_US" target="_blank">DAVx⁵</a> for syncing with&nbsp;<a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.dmfs.tasks" target="_blank">OpenTasks</a>&nbsp;as the client); and works well with a boatload of different applications such as <a href="https://www.thunderbird.net/" target="_blank">Thunderbird</a>, <a href="https://wiki.gnome.org/Apps/Evolution/" target="_blank">Evolution</a>, <a href="https://kontact.kde.org/" target="_blank">Kontact</a> and <a href="https://github.com/pimutils/khal" target="_blank">khal</a>.
  </p>

  <p>
    This cleaned up my workflow and shrunk server maintenance as I consolidated all hosted tools down to Nextcloud which is simple to keep up to date. I changed the way I store information by using Apple's <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/reminders/id1108187841" target="_blank">Reminders</a> app on my phone and Evolution or Thunderbird on my PC. Previously I saved the articles with Wallabag or Pocket. When I inevitably came back months later to do some mapping, a full reread was required to find the needed information. Now, I copy and paste the needed information into a task making it easy to pull up when the time comes. This also allows for reminder alerts and due dates. I have task lists for books, films, music, openstreetmap mapping, learning, work and home construction. Text tags are placed at the bottom of the task so I can search for the term later and have them appear.
  </p>

  <p>
    Realizing earlier this year that all of my goals can be accomplished with my existing tools was an epiphany. After 5 years of hoping this or that service would add this or that feature I discovered everything is already in place. The solution to a problem that has been dragging on for years was in sight and only required a reevaluation of what is already in use.
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Grid Milwaukee&#x27;s Bus Routes</title>
        <author>
            <name>Colin White</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/grid-milwaukees-bus-routes.html"/>
        <id>https://MkeCountyBlog.com/grid-milwaukees-bus-routes.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/4/gridMilwaukeePostHeader.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="MapHub"/>
            <category term="MCTS"/>
            <category term="Grid"/>
            <category term="Bus Routes"/>

        <updated>2020-12-26T11:35:56-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/4/gridMilwaukeePostHeader.png" alt="MCB&#x27;s grid map overlay." />
                    Inspired by an article from Strong Towns discussing Indianapolis' new route trials it provides an alternative system design. To explore a prospective&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/4/gridMilwaukeePostHeader.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="MCB&#x27;s grid map overlay." /></p>
                <div class="post__iframe"><iframe loading="lazy" width="100%" height="576" src="https://maphub.net/embed/89503?legend=1" frameborder="0"></iframe></div>
<p>Inspired by <a href="https://www.strongtowns.org/journal/2020/1/24/how-to-get-to-great-bus-service-in-a-car-dominated-place" title="How To Get To Great Bus Service In A Car-Dominated Place" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">an article from Strong Towns</a> discussing Indianapolis' new route trials it provides an alternative system design. To explore a prospective grid patterned map for Milwaukee County click the button above overlaying the map. The orange lines are East-West routes (EW) and the green lines are North-South routes (NS). For the most part each route crosses the entire county from EW or NS. Riding the bus to any destination would require knowing the cross-streets. For example: to get from Northwestern Mutual's new building downtown to the Mitchell Park Domes you would get on a bus at Mason Street / Prospect Avenue (the Wisconsin Avenue turn around), ride west along Wisconsin Avenue and transfer to the 27th Street line heading South. The same route using the existing lines is shown below.</p>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center" ><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/4/downtownToDomes.png" alt="MCTS' current route from Downtown to the Domes" width="358" height="700" sizes="100vw" srcset="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/4/responsive/downtownToDomes-xs.webp 300w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/4/responsive/downtownToDomes-sm.webp 480w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/4/responsive/downtownToDomes-md.webp 768w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/4/responsive/downtownToDomes-lg.webp 1024w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/4/responsive/downtownToDomes-xl.webp 1360w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/4/responsive/downtownToDomes-2xl.webp 1600w">
<figcaption >Your options for getting to the domes from downtown with the current routes. ©Ride MCTS</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>MCTS's existing routes are a bit more sporadic; utilizing a route number or color and destinations (ex: GoldLine Wisconsin Ave - UWM or 21 North Ave.) They have done a good job connecting major amenities but lack the ability to connect riders to every area in the county. Going from Bayside to Brown Deer takes 5-10 minutes by car and 1.5 hours by bus. Franklin and Oak Creek are nearly unreachable. The county's budget is tight every year due mostly to poor pension related decision making from the past so routes have been slowly disappearing or shrinking. MCTS, our county supervisors and our county executive do a good job maintaining the current routes to connect as many people as possible to key destinations (generally prioritizing job access) despite the lack of funds. Unfortunately the current setup appears to create a downward spiral of higher fares and lower ridership (much like the rest of the country.)</p>
<figure class="post__image post__image--full" ><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/4/mctsMap.png" alt="2020 Milwaukee County Transit Guide" width="2323" height="1941" sizes="100vw" srcset="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/4/responsive/mctsMap-xs.webp 300w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/4/responsive/mctsMap-sm.webp 480w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/4/responsive/mctsMap-md.webp 768w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/4/responsive/mctsMap-lg.webp 1024w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/4/responsive/mctsMap-xl.webp 1360w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/4/responsive/mctsMap-2xl.webp 1600w">
<figcaption ><a href="https://www.ridemcts.com/getattachment/Routes-Schedules/System-Map/2020-System-Map.pdf?lang=en-US" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" title="2020 Milwaukee County Transit Guide">2020 Milwaukee County Transit Guide</a> - ©MCTS</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Influenced by MCTS advertising and stories about bus drivers, I began riding during the summer of 2019. My wife and I moved from downtown to Bayside a few years ago after which she started a new job in the city. We enjoy eating at various restaurants all around the city (keep it in the county!) so in order to avoid driving two cars home after dinner I decided to start taking the bus down to meet her. MCTS is a great transportation option and I now take the bus to the city multiple times a week. The drivers are friendly, helpful, and know the different routes well enough to help a turned around newcomer (such a myself.) It also encourages me to get outside and walk more. It takes at least 30 minutes to walk to the nearest bus stop from my home. Another example is last fall when I got off at the east end of Brady street and walked west to Van Buren to meet my wife.</p>
<p>The grid map represents what I believe our community should work towards. Every part of the county is fully accessible allowing people to leave their cars at home and get to every part of the county. The general idea at the start was to have each route separated by at most 3 blocks. This was mostly maintained but the south side is more spread out due to limitations of the existing street grid. The bus as a primary mode of transportation becomes practical for virtually everyone and finding your way to a destination is greatly simplified. Every single commercial, industrial and retail area (the jobs) is connected with the grid.</p>
<p>In addition to changing the current routes I believe the county should utilize bus lanes as well as a system that forces traffic lights to change for buses as they approach an intersection; allowing them to maintain a constant speed along each route. This will help maintain a more predictable schedule for riders and speed up trips to further entice new ridership. A bus should pass each stop every 10 or 15 minutes. The stops are not mapped but assume every intersection of a NS and EW route is a stop with only a handful of additional stops needed.</p>
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Milwaukee_County_Transit_System#Bus_fleet" title="Milwaukee County Transit System - Bus fleet" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">According to Wikipedia</a>, Milwaukee currently has 369 active buses. I have mapped 27 EW routes and 49 NS routes. Assuming 3 buses per EW route 81 buses would be active at any given time. Milwaukee County's shape is tall and thin so the much longer NS routes double the number of buses per route compared with the EW routes. Assuming 6 buses per NS route you would have 294 buses active at any given time.  A few individual routes could utilize fewer buses and maintain the same frequency such as West Bradley Road which dies in River Hills where the Milwaukee River blocks its passage. </p>
<p>A few key questions remam unanswered. How many of the currently active 369 buses are in use at any given time? A decent amount probably are rotated regularly in and out of service for maintenance. What is the breakdown of MCTS' $160 million budget? I assume most funding comes from federal grants, county/state funding, with a bit from rider fares (<a href="https://urbanmilwaukee.com/2020/02/27/urban-ideas-make-mcts-free-during-dnc/" title="Make MCTS Free During DNC" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">update</a>: fares annually contribute $30,771,208 or 19% of total funding - more than expected!) In my mind income from fares would very likely increase with the grid as more of the county would become accessible and the utility of the system would grow significantly. Why pay all of that money for Uber or Lyft when I can take the bus for $2 (or less!)? Why pay for two cars and maintenance when I can go everywhere with the bus? Has a public private partnership been explored for operating and expanding bus service in our area? </p>
<p>While I personally believe this would be a fantastic system, I can already imagine the push back from those that don't want buses near their homes. It would largely follow the arguments used against apartments, building density or most (revenue generating) change of any kind introduced outside of downtown including crime, noise, environment, etc. It is impossible to improve upon the problems plaguing our area without trying something new.</p>
<p>In the rare instances where our local politicians, against popular opinion, have moved forward with changes that they believe to be in the community's long term best interests these fears never seem to actualize. I still recall the fear from people when Best Buy was proposed for RiverPoint Village near where I grew up. The same arguments were vehemently presented but Best Buy was able to come anyways (probably since it was already zoned for retail.) The area remains largely the same now as it was then and nobody seems to think about or discuss it anymore.</p>
<p>I believe the result of implementing a county-wide grid bus system would follow the same path; a loud opposition followed by everyone adapting to a significantly more useful transportation system that has little to no negative impact on their lives and neighborhoods. As with any idea, there's needs to be leadership that is willing to try things that may be unpopular.</p>
<p>Edit 2020/04/27: Cleanup the intro a bit. Update post with information from the always useful <a href="https://urbanmilwaukee.com/" title="Urban Milwaukee" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Urban Milwaukee</a>.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Switching to the Brave Web Browser</title>
        <author>
            <name>Colin White</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/switching_to_the_brave_web_browser.html"/>
        <id>https://MkeCountyBlog.com/switching_to_the_brave_web_browser.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/3/logotype_alt.svg" medium="image" />
            <category term="Web Browser"/>
            <category term="Privacy"/>
            <category term="Open Source"/>
            <category term="Firefox"/>
            <category term="Brave"/>

        <updated>2020-10-18T22:52:27-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/3/logotype_alt.svg" alt="Brave browser&#x27;s logo, a stylized lion&#x27;s head on the left, with an orange background." />
                    A lesson I learned while teaching my Mom some computer tricks is that I should probably begin with what a (web)&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/3/logotype_alt.svg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="Brave browser&#x27;s logo, a stylized lion&#x27;s head on the left, with an orange background." /></p>
                <p>A lesson I learned while teaching my Mom some computer tricks is that I should probably begin with what a (web) browser is. To do this, I'll start with a somewhat technical definition from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_browser" title="Web browser" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Wikipedia</a>, "A web browser (commonly referred to as a browser) is a software application for accessing information on the World Wide Web." Great, now lets simplify that a bit. You will likely recognize names such as Chrome, Firefox, Edge or Safari; these are different browsers. You open it up and use it to shop on Amazon or Etsy; Duck things on <a href="https://duckduckgo.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">duckduckgo</a>; checkout stuff on Pinterest, Reddit or Facebook, etc. You tell the browser what you want to see by typing in an URL, (for example <a href="https://google.com">https://google.com</a>) or more likely just type in a search term and off you go!</p>
<p>Hopefully you now recognize what a browser is but I imagine now you're wondering so what? Who cares what browser I use? For the most part it doesn't make much of a difference. They may use slightly different styling, or have some special feature you never use, but essentially they all take you to the same place. They connect you with websites and hopefully stay out of your way.</p>
<p>I will pick on Chrome for this paragraph because it is mostly developed by the largest internet advertising company on the planet, Google. If I remember correctly, Chrome was created to speed up web browsing and improve browser security. Around 2010 Internet Explorer was full of security holes and Firefox was slow and bloated so the user experience was not particularly good. Also, Google wanted to be sure that the Google search engine remained the default option at least in Chrome since search ads drive a great deal of their revenue; IE or Firefox switching their default search provider at the time could have been very harmful to Google's bottom line.</p>
<p>The green line on the chart below shows the change in Chrome's market share from 2009-2020. Today it controls roughly 65% of the browser market which gives Google a great deal of power in discussions about what standards are introduced and adopted and how they are implemented. Chrome is very slow to adopt the privacy features built-in to their competitor's browsers as they would negatively effect their advertising income. This allows them to better identify and track people in order to serve them more targeted advertisements and make more money.</p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/3/StatCounter-browser-ww-monthly-200901-202002.png" alt="Web Browser Market Share Worldwide between January 2009 and February 2020" width="1280" height="720" sizes="100vw" srcset="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/3/responsive/StatCounter-browser-ww-monthly-200901-202002-xs.webp 300w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/3/responsive/StatCounter-browser-ww-monthly-200901-202002-sm.webp 480w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/3/responsive/StatCounter-browser-ww-monthly-200901-202002-md.webp 768w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/3/responsive/StatCounter-browser-ww-monthly-200901-202002-lg.webp 1024w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/3/responsive/StatCounter-browser-ww-monthly-200901-202002-xl.webp 1360w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/3/responsive/StatCounter-browser-ww-monthly-200901-202002-2xl.webp 1600w"></figure>
<p>Chrome is built on top of the open-source Chromium browser. Chrome is essentially Chromium with a Google sweatshirt. Everyone is free to use and change Chromium but that sweatshirt is hiding all of the extra stuff Google adds to build the proprietary Chrome. The source code is closed off so no one can see. You can think of Brave as Chromium with a completely different sweatshirt with all of its unique features open to everyone allowing us see, change and help improve it. So you get all of the security and speed benefits without most of the Google enabled tracking and privacy invading aspects of Chrome. </p>
<p>That is the basic building blocks of the Brave browser. <strong>The truly revolutionary portion is their long-term goal of replacing the massive user tracking and profiling system that currently powers the internet economy with a privacy preserving advertising system built into the browser.</strong> Most internet services such as Gmail, Facebook, Instagram, Tiktok, newspapers, magazines, blogs, etc are funded through advertising. This is why a service like Hulu has a free tier with advertising while Netflix always requires you to pay. The trouble is, this business model incentivizes massive amounts of surveillance across the internet.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>"Google controls about <a href="https://gs.statcounter.com/browser-market-share/mobile/worldwide">62% of mobile browsers</a>, <a href="https://gs.statcounter.com/browser-market-share/desktop/worldwide">69% of desktop browsers</a>, and the operating systems on <a href="https://www.netmarketshare.com/operating-system-market-share.aspx?options=%7B%22filter%22%3A%7B%22%24and%22%3A%5B%7B%22deviceType%22%3A%7B%22%24in%22%3A%5B%22Mobile%22%5D%7D%7D%5D%7D%2C%22dateLabel%22%3A%22Trend%22%2C%22attributes%22%3A%22share%22%2C%22group%22%3A%22platform%22%2C%22sort%22%3A%7B%22share%22%3A-1%7D%2C%22id%22%3A%22platformsMobile%22%2C%22dateInterval%22%3A%22Monthly%22%2C%22dateStart%22%3A%222019-02%22%2C%22dateEnd%22%3A%222020-01%22%2C%22segments%22%3A%22-1000%22%7D">71% of mobile devices</a> in the world. <a href="https://gs.statcounter.com/search-engine-market-share">92% of internet searches</a> go through Google and <a href="https://www.businessofapps.com/data/youtube-statistics/">73% of American adults</a> use YouTube. Google runs code on approximately <a href="https://w3techs.com/technologies/details/ta-googleanalytics">85% of sites on the Web</a> and inside <a href="https://www.statista.com/statistics/1035623/leading-mobile-app-ad-network-sdks-android/">as many as 94%</a> of apps in the Play store. It collects data about users’ every click, tap, query, and movement from all of those sources and more." </p>
<p><a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2020/03/google-says-it-doesnt-sell-your-data-heres-how-company-shares-monetizes-and" title="Google Says It Doesn’t 'Sell' Your Data. Here’s How the Company Shares, Monetizes, and Exploits It." target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" style="font-family: -apple-system, BlinkMacSystemFont, Arial, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Oxygen, Ubuntu, Cantarell, 'Fira Sans', 'Droid Sans', 'Helvetica Neue', sans-serif, 'Apple Color Emoji', 'Segoe UI Emoji', 'Segoe UI Symbol'; font-size: inherit;">EFF - Google Says It Doesn't 'Sell' Your Data   </a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Google and Facebook and dozens of other data companies encourage website owners to use their scripts on their websites so that they can track user activity everywhere they go on the internet and target them ads. By default, Brave blocks these trackers and identifying techniques to speed up browsing and protect users from this ridiculousness. Below is a list of tracking scripts blocked on a visit to the <a href="https://jsonline.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Milwaukee Journal Sentinel</a> website. Amazon, Facebook, Google and a sea of others are all utilized; drastically slowing down the web page's load time and adding a lot of annoying pop ups and videos to the website.</p>
<p><span class="BlockedInfoRowStats-sc-u7266a iTuUMq"><strong>What Brave Blocks on Milwaukee Journal Sentinel's website</strong></span></p>
<p><span class="BlockedInfoRowStats-sc-u7266a iTuUMq">31 </span><span class="BlockedListSummaryText-sc-1lnzx8i SlhMV">Cross-site trackers blocked</span></p>
<ul class="BlockedListStatic-sc-14k04lq dqWHj">
<li class="BlockedListItem-sc-1xbwfrg eEkjIk">https://www.gannett-cdn.com/uxstatic/jsonline/uscp-web-static-4525.20.0/js/partner/show_ads.js</li>
<li class="BlockedListItem-sc-1xbwfrg eEkjIk">https://try.abtasty.com/bcf3f16fe6dfff2da9b2400d218df47c.js</li>
<li class="BlockedListItem-sc-1xbwfrg eEkjIk">https://cdn.taboola.com/libtrc/gannett-network/loader.js</li>
<li class="BlockedListItem-sc-1xbwfrg eEkjIk">https://c2.taboola.com/nr/gannettcompany-jsonline/newsroom.js</li>
<li class="BlockedListItem-sc-1xbwfrg eEkjIk">https://cdn.taboola.com/libtrc/static/thumbnails/3aadbb71016ecd7a194bbe2791777e9a.png</li>
<li class="BlockedListItem-sc-1xbwfrg eEkjIk">https://confiant-integrations.global.ssl.fastly.net/r5TdgVvkbv-PeaJCKaQfCh5Xsto/gpt_and_prebid_v3l/config.js</li>
<li class="BlockedListItem-sc-1xbwfrg eEkjIk">https://pubads.g.doubleclick.net/gampad/adx?iu=%2F7103%2Fswg%2Fpts_wi-milwaukee-C1258&amp;sz=1x1&amp;ref=&amp;cookie=undefined&amp;c=141688919367667&amp;tile=1&amp;u_tz=-300</li>
<li class="BlockedListItem-sc-1xbwfrg eEkjIk">https://securepubads.g.doubleclick.net/tag/js/gpt.js</li>
<li class="BlockedListItem-sc-1xbwfrg eEkjIk">https://c.amazon-adsystem.com/aax2/apstag.js</li>
<li class="BlockedListItem-sc-1xbwfrg eEkjIk">https://cdn.adsafeprotected.com/iasPET.1.js</li>
<li class="BlockedListItem-sc-1xbwfrg eEkjIk">https://js-sec.indexww.com/ht/p/184808-89514051626416.js</li>
<li class="BlockedListItem-sc-1xbwfrg eEkjIk">https://www.gannett-cdn.com/partner/vendor/pbjsandwich-v1.min.js</li>
<li class="BlockedListItem-sc-1xbwfrg eEkjIk">https://connect.facebook.net/en_US/sdk.js</li>
<li class="BlockedListItem-sc-1xbwfrg eEkjIk">https://content-static.gannett.com/OpinionLab/oo_style.js</li>
<li class="BlockedListItem-sc-1xbwfrg eEkjIk">https://content-static.gannett.com/OpinionLab/oo_engine.min.js</li>
<li class="BlockedListItem-sc-1xbwfrg eEkjIk">https://static.adsafeprotected.com/iasADX.js</li>
<li class="BlockedListItem-sc-1xbwfrg eEkjIk">https://7q1z79gxsi.global.ssl.fastly.net/7q1z79gxsi-m.js</li>
<li class="BlockedListItem-sc-1xbwfrg eEkjIk">https://7q1z79gxsi.global.ssl.fastly.net/7q1z79gxsi-c.js</li>
<li class="BlockedListItem-sc-1xbwfrg eEkjIk">https://dpm.demdex.net/id?d_visid_ver=3.1.2&amp;d_fieldgroup=AAM&amp;d_rtbd=json&amp;d_ver=2&amp;d_orgid=CF4957F555EE9B727F000101%40AdobeOrg&amp;d_nsid=0&amp;d_mid=24905135920613042071094820707358437236&amp;ts=1584585491334</li>
<li class="BlockedListItem-sc-1xbwfrg eEkjIk">https://cdn.krxd.net/controltag/suw9jm9mz.js</li>
<li class="BlockedListItem-sc-1xbwfrg eEkjIk">https://cdn.parsely.com/keys/jsonline.com/p.js</li>
<li class="BlockedListItem-sc-1xbwfrg eEkjIk">https://sb.scorecardresearch.com/beacon.js</li>
<li class="BlockedListItem-sc-1xbwfrg eEkjIk">https://pixel.mathtag.com/event/js?mt_pp=1&amp;mt_adid=114093</li>
<li class="BlockedListItem-sc-1xbwfrg eEkjIk">https://www.googleadservices.com/pagead/conversion_async.js</li>
<li class="BlockedListItem-sc-1xbwfrg eEkjIk">https://b-code.liadm.com/a-048w.min.js</li>
<li class="BlockedListItem-sc-1xbwfrg eEkjIk">https://cdn.keywee.co/dist/analytics.min.js</li>
<li class="BlockedListItem-sc-1xbwfrg eEkjIk">https://resources.xg4ken.com/js/v2/ktag.js?tid=KT%E2%80%90N2B92%E2%80%903EB</li>
<li class="BlockedListItem-sc-1xbwfrg eEkjIk">https://connect.facebook.net/en_US/fbevents.js</li>
<li class="BlockedListItem-sc-1xbwfrg eEkjIk">https://10870841.collect.igodigital.com/collect.js</li>
<li class="BlockedListItem-sc-1xbwfrg eEkjIk">https://srepdata.jsonline.com/b/ss/globaldesktopmobilesite/1/JS-2.9.0/s0586757838856</li>
<li class="BlockedListItem-sc-1xbwfrg eEkjIk">https://www.google-analytics.com/analytics.js</li>
</ul>
<p>At this point you might be uneasy but still think, "hey, they need to earn money to pay for their reporting. There aren't that many options for decent, local, investigative journalism and the newspaper industry has been hammered over the years (by Google &amp; Facebook as it turns out.)" This is where Brave stands out from the other browsers. Instead of just blocking ads, Brave users are able to earn money in the form of Basic Attention Tokens (BAT) for allowing Brave to display ads occasionally. You are able to adjust how frequently they appear and are not required to enable them; it is an opt-in choice. At this point, the ads display as notifications on your computer or phone and disappear after a few seconds. When ads popup, you earn 70% of the ad revenue while the other 30% goes to Brave providing them with a dedicated funding source. Firefox, the third most used browser, is another open source browser with some ad-blocking but they rely on search engine providers for a large chunk of their annual funding leaving them with an unstable year to year budget and an uncertain future. They face the same problem as newspapers: since less people are using them, they get paid less for the default search engine rights and have less money to compete.</p>
<p>Every month Brave distributes a user-adjustable percentage of your BAT to the websites you visit based on the amount of time you spent at each site. When the ad is displayed, you earn BAT; no need to click on the ad if you're not interested. The tracking and ad targeting is all done locally on your computer and is never sent anywhere or shared with anyone. This allows website owners and content creators to earn money without strong-arming users into giving information to Google and Facebook to sell to ad companies. When you browse Github, Reddit, Twitter or YouTube, the content creators are able to receive BAT instead of just the website operator. This means that Timmy will get BAT for his YouTube video when people watch it, not just YouTube.</p>
<figure class="post__image post__image--center" ><img loading="lazy" src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/3/braveNewTab.png" alt="Screenshot of Brave's new page" width="1920" height="1054" sizes="100vw" srcset="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/3/responsive/braveNewTab-xs.webp 300w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/3/responsive/braveNewTab-sm.webp 480w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/3/responsive/braveNewTab-md.webp 768w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/3/responsive/braveNewTab-lg.webp 1024w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/3/responsive/braveNewTab-xl.webp 1360w ,https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/3/responsive/braveNewTab-2xl.webp 1600w">
<figcaption >Brave's new tab page where you can see what's been blocked and how much time you've saved. ©MCB</figcaption>
</figure>
<p>Brave seems like a near perfect compromise that benefits users, advertisers and content creators. Users continue to get free content as well as <a href="https://www.ghacks.net/2020/02/25/study-finds-brave-to-be-the-most-private-browser/" title="Study finds Brave to be the most private browser" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">the most private by default browser out there</a>; advertisers can continue to sell their wares; content creators can earn money for endeavors; all without the massive, privacy invading, information dragnet currently in place. I hope to see Brave usage increase and more websites sign on; especially in Milwaukee. Some companies certainly seem to be on board as lately larger companie's ads are showing up. User growth appears to be healthy as well; <a href="https://brave.com/brave-passes-10m-mau/" title="Brave Passes 10 Million Monthly Active Users, and Sees 19% Growth since 1.0 Launch" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">passing 10 million</a> last December.</p>
<p>Of the different Milwaukee websites I frequent, <a href="https://urbanmilwaukee.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Urban Milwaukee</a> seems to have the most balanced approach with less tracking for paid members compared to free users. <a href="https://onmilwaukee.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">OnMilwaukee.com</a> unfortunately has no paid tier so tracking for everybody! <a href="https://milwaukeerecord.com/">Milwaukee Record</a> uses broadstreetads.com which uses local advertising which is a plus. All three, regardless of tier, use the ubiquitous Google Analytics found on a large swath of the internet. Google Analytics monitors mouse movements, clicks, time spent on pages and much more; sending it all back to Google servers. The City of Milwaukee and Milwaukee County websites both have Google mixed in as well. Milwaukee County Blog use a locally hosted instance of <a href="https://matomo.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Matomo</a> so nobody gets any information but MCB and it is setup with some anonymizing settings enabled since I'm only interested in the number of visitors and if they come back (so far nobody but bots 😥.)</p>
<p>Even if Brave doesn't sound like your cup of tea, I highly encourage people to install uBO-Scope (<a href="https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/ubo-scope/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Firefox users</a> / <a href="https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/ubo-scope/bbdpgcaljkaaigfcomhidmneffjjjfgp" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Brave &amp; Chrome users</a>) so you can see all of the different companies tracking your every move online. If seeing all of the tracking doesn't make Brave or an ad blocker like uBlock Origin more appealing to you then so be it.</p>
<figure class="post__image"><a href="https://brave.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/3/brave-bat-partnership.svg" alt="Brave logo &amp; BAT logo" width="1920" height="387"></figure></a></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Overlooked Privacy Issues With The Hop&#x27;s New Kiosks</title>
        <author>
            <name>Colin White</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/overlooked-privacy-issues-with-the-hops-new-kiosks.html"/>
        <id>https://MkeCountyBlog.com/overlooked-privacy-issues-with-the-hops-new-kiosks.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/2/Kiosk-Rendering.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="The Hop"/>
            <category term="Surveillance"/>
            <category term="Privacy"/>
            <category term="MPD"/>

        <updated>2021-01-01T10:55:45-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/2/Kiosk-Rendering.png" alt="" />
                    A recent press release from The Hop offers details about the 8.5 foot "smart kiosks" being introduced to Milwaukee’s streetcar&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://MkeCountyBlog.com/media/posts/2/Kiosk-Rendering.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>A recent <a href="https://urbanmilwaukee.com/pressrelease/the-hop-unveils-citypost-smart-kiosk-initiative/" title="The Hop Unveils CityPost Smart Kiosk Initiative" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">press release</a> from The Hop offers details about the 8.5 foot "smart kiosks" being introduced to Milwaukee’s streetcar stops beginning in May. Cities around the world have been forming relationships with companies such as Smart City Media to create new sources of income for municipalities as well as bridge the gap between online advertising and people’s habits in the physical world.</p>
<p>The idea normally revolves around using cameras, sensors and various other tracking techniques to connect people's online advertising profiles to their actions in the physical world while offering a somewhat useful tool in return at no cost to the municipality. Did Sam go to the store and buy that home mushroom farm we advertised on Instagram?</p>
<p>These agreements often create concerns as a result of privacy and security considerations being an afterthought of companies and municipalities. When companies that specialize in advertising offer something for free, there is a trade off that often comes at the expense of an individual's privacy. When a budget strapped city such as Milwaukee is offered up to $500,000 annually at no expense, they tend not to focus on the details.</p>
<p>Should a casual walk down the street require surveillance by the Milwaukee Police Department? Do these kiosks use beacons or WiFi-tracking techniques to track where people are going regardless of whether they connected to the WiFi and agreed to the terms? Answers to the questions below could help address these sorts of concerns.</p>
<ol>
<li>What and where is the privacy policy for these devices?</li>
<li>What types of data are collected?</li>
<li>How and why is it collected?</li>
<li>How is the collected data anonymized?</li>
<li>Is tracking limited to users that connect to the WiFi?</li>
<li>Is the video and audio recording 24/7 or activated by the emergency feature?</li>
<li>Who owns the video and audio data? Where and how is it stored? What is the retention policy? How will MPD use the video and audio feeds?</li>
<li>What restrictions are in place on Smart City Media's usage and/or sale of collected data?</li>
<li>What oversight is there to assure Smart City Media is following the terms of the contract in relation to data use, privacy and retention policies?</li>
<li>How frequently are these devices' <a href="https://www.wired.com/story/visitor-management-system-vulnerabilities/" title="The Overlooked Security Threat of Sign-In Kiosks" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">software and OS updated</a>?</li>
<li>Who owns the streetcar tracking and arrival time data?</li>
</ol>
<p>Smart City Media appears to be an honest company that provides useful products and provides a fair bargain with municipalities around the country. However, more information needs to be provided. The video surveillance aspect is particularly troubling as law enforcement should be limited to monitoring individuals suspected of crimes after getting a warrant; not broad, indiscriminate monitoring of large swaths of the city. As Bruce Schneier states in his book <em>Secrets and Lies, </em><strong>"it is poor civic hygiene to install technologies that could someday facilitate a police state."</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://www.chicagotribune.com/suburbs/aurora-beacon-news/ct-abn-aurora-kiosks-st-0925-story.html"></a>Several other cities reversed course on their smart kiosks idea. In 2017, Seattle’s mayor <a href="https://www.geekwire.com/2018/seattles-plan-bring-intersection-wifi-kiosks-bus-stop-makeovers-stalled/" title="Why Seattle’s plan to bring Intersection WiFi kiosks and bus stop makeovers stalled" target="null">rejected an initial proposal</a> from Intersection. Her communications director stated,</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Mayor Durkan had significant concerns with both the privacy and data policies — specifically what data was collected, how it was stored, what tracking was possible, and how ads were targeted.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>New York City had privacy issues exposed with their <a href="https://theintercept.com/2018/09/08/linknyc-free-wifi-kiosks/" title="ARE NEW YORK’S FREE LINKNYC INTERNET KIOSKS TRACKING YOUR MOVEMENTS?" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">smart payphone kiosks</a> installed throughout the city. “LinkNYC kiosks, at no cost to the city, would provide free internet coverage to anyone walking by.” The company, working with NYC in this case, also accidentally uploaded some testing source-code to Github,</p>
<blockquote>...the “LinkNYC Mobile Observation” code collects the user’s longitude and latitude, as well as the user’s browser type, operating system, device type, device identifiers, and full URL clickstreams (including date and time) and aggregates this information into a database. In Meyers’s view, this code — along with the functions of the “RxLocation” codebase — suggests that the company is interested in tracking the locations of Wi-Fi users in real time. If such code were run on a mobile app or kiosk, he said, the company would be able to make advertisements available in real time based on where and who someone was, and that this would constitute a potential violation of the company’s <a href="https://www.link.nyc/privacy-policy.html" title="LinkNYC Privacy Policy" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">privacy policy</a>. In 2016, LinkNYC’s privacy policy made it clear that it did not collect information about users’ precise locations. “However,” it states, “we know where we provide WiFi services, so when you use the services we can determine your general location.</blockquote>
<p>To reiterate, Smart City Media does not have a record of malfeasance that is readily discoverable through a quick duckduckgo search. That being said, it will benefit residents, visitors and our representatives to slow down, get clear answers to the above questions, verify that the proper safeguards are in place and that excessively intrusive technologies will not be introduced into our daily lives. Advertisements, like police, are necessary and beneficial to society but they should not be profiling our every click and movement (unless we have done something to truly justify it 😉.)</p>
<hr>
<p><em>03/16/2020 - Edited to add question #10 and to perform some small grammatical fixes.</em></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
